<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Marketing | Brian Armstrong]]></title>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/categories/marketing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-11T21:00:55-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Armstrong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Something I coded up for fun...]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/something-i-coded-up-for-fun/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-22T02:33:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/something-i-coded-up-for-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I put <a href="http://mybestpic.org">this website</a> together over the last few weeks that I thought you might like.</p>

<p>It's quite simple.  Basically you can hold a "photo contest" and see which photo your friends like best.</p>

<p>Here are a few examples...</p>

<ol>
<li>Choose a photo of yourself.</li>
</ol>


<p><a href="http://mybestpic.org/lTmQAr"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/02/Screen-shot-2011-02-21-at-6.24.24-PM-500x360.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<ol>
<li>Choose artwork or travel photos.</li>
</ol>


<p><a href="http://mybestpic.org/0AbTrQ"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/02/Screen-shot-2011-02-21-at-6.22.17-PM-500x360.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<ol>
<li>For downright silliness.</li>
</ol>


<p><a href="http://mybestpic.org/ac8crN"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/02/Screen-shot-2011-02-21-at-6.23.10-PM-500x360.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I'll do a follow up post in a week or so with more details on the idea and results of the site.  But for now...</p>

<h1><a href="http://mybestpic.org">Try it out</a> and let me know what you think!</h1>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Controversial Is Good Marketing]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/being-controversial-is-good-marketing/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-22T23:34:37-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/being-controversial-is-good-marketing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started thinking about this topic lately.  Here are 3 random examples I've noticed - see if you can draw any conclusions or find others.</p>

<h1>1. Ricky Gervais</h1>

<p>He caused an uproar lately by insulting lots of famous people while hosting the Golden Globes.  Backstory <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=flBFagW5vC8">here</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=flBFagW5vC8"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/01/Screen-shot-2011-01-22-at-2.37.13-PM-500x306.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>There is no doubt he angered a bunch of people.  But did this hurt or help his career?</p>

<p>On the one hand he may not be invited back to host the Golden Globes again next year.  On the other hand, most Americans probably didn't know who he was before this week.  They do now, and his appeal as a comedian just went way up.</p>

<p>Apparently, there are lots of people out there who also think Hollywood is ridiculous and full of itself.  These people rushed to his defense and became loyal fans overnight.</p>

<p><strong>Being polarizing means for every enemy you make you gain a devoted fan.  When you remain neutral and try to appeal to both sides, you offend no one but also aren't remembered by anyone.</strong></p>

<p>He might not have had a fun week, but I bet his career just had a net win.</p>

<h1>2. OkCupid.com</h1>

<p>Their blog seems almost entirely centered on the idea of controversy as a marketing tool.  Here are a few of their headlines lately:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://blog.okcupid.com/index.php/the-real-stuff-white-people-like/">The Real Stuff White People Like</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://blog.okcupid.com/index.php/rape-fantasies-and-hygiene-by-state/">Rape Fantasies and Hygiene By State</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://blog.okcupid.com/index.php/your-race-affects-whether-people-write-you-back/">How Your Race Affects Whether People Write You Back</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:WJ1dKFMXD-AJ:blog.okcupid.com/index.php/why-you-should-never-pay-for-online-dating/+why+you+should+never+pay+for+online+dating&amp;cd=1&amp;hl=en&amp;ct=clnk&amp;gl=us">Why You Should Never Pay For Online Dating</a> (where they argue quite convincingly why most online dating sites are a scam)</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Their posts average probably 500 comments and are massively reposted all over the internet.</p>

<p>However, there is one key difference between their posts and most controversial discussions on the net: <strong>their posts are based on hard data, not opinion</strong>.</p>

<p>The guys behind the blog are huge math nerds, and have a wealth of data at their disposal from the dating site (people fill out profiles etc).  So most of their posts take the tone of "we're not saying this is right or wrong, but here is the truth about what the world is like".</p>

<p>This is a powerful position to come from because if someone wants to disagree they have to argue with your math, and can't appeal to emotion.  So I think there is a good lesson here: <strong>if you're going to be controversial, back it up with hard data.</strong></p>

<h1>3. Apple</h1>

<p>Steve jobs puts it a different way in this classic video where he lays out Apple's marketing strategy.</p>

<p>He says every great brand isn't afraid to stand for something.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vmG9jzCHtSQ"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/01/Screen-shot-2011-01-22-at-3.09.43-PM-500x307.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>"Stand for something" is less pejorative than being controversial, but it's really the same thing.  If you stand for something, then you aren't afraid to disagree and you think the other way of doing it is wrong.</p>

<p>And they live it by building opinionated software and hardware.  Want more than one USB drive on your MacBook air?  Sorry can't have it.  Want a discount Apple computer under $500?  They don't want your business.</p>

<p>I think the lesson here is clear.  <strong>In business, trying to be all things to all people just makes you unremarkable to everyone.</strong> People become loyal fans of companies that stand for something.  By polarizing people you'll wins fans (along with the enemies) and stick in people's minds.</p>

<p>I think a healthy dose of speaking your mind can be a great tool to jumpstart any brand.  What do you think?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Get Your Customers To Refer Their Friends]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/how-to-get-your-customers-to-refer-their-friends/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-25T19:41:06-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/how-to-get-your-customers-to-refer-their-friends</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was reading <a href="http://bit.ly/9x5THt">this presentation by the Dropbox.com Founder</a>, Drew Houston, the other day and the most interesting part about it was that most of their marketing with Adwords and conventional approaches completely failed.</p>

<p>Yet Dropbox has over 4 million users.  So how did they do it?</p>

<p>Apparently it was almost entirely word of mouth - but they did it in a smart way.</p>

<p><a href="http://bit.ly/9x5THt"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/04/Screen-shot-2010-04-25-at-12.12.31-PM.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>You can click above to see the full set of slides (they are worth reading).  But one important point that stood out to me was the 2-sided incentive for referrals that he mentioned above.</p>

<p>I logged in to Dropbox to see what it looked like and here it is:</p>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/04/Screen-shot-2010-04-25-at-12.16.51-PM.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/04/Screen-shot-2010-04-25-at-12.16.51-PM.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>The key here is that he is giving them more <strong>storage</strong> as the reward and not <strong>money</strong>.  I like this for a few reasons:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>It's closer to what Dropbox users actually want.</p></li>
<li><p>It's cheaper for Dropbox to give this away because they are dealing in trade.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>It's sort of like if you ask your friend to give you a ride to the airport, and when you get there you pull out your wallet and give him $10.  He'd probably feel insulted - it cheapens the act of kindness.  But if you give him a ride the next time he needs one, or return the favor in some other way that isn't money, then it's all good.</p>

<p>Sometimes money isn't the best gift.</p>

<p>So with this in mind I started thinking about how I could improve my own site, <a href="http://www.universitytutor.com">UniversityTutor</a>.  My current referral program pays tutors $3/month to refer other tutors.  But those other tutors not only have to signup, they also have to upgrade - which only 1-2% of them do.  So it's tough for tutors to make much doing this, and $3 isn't very motivating.</p>

<p>This weekend I took a few hours to change UniversityTutor's referral program to more of a Dropbox model.  The free account on UniversityTutor is based on the number of job requests you get (first 3 are free, after that you can upgrade) instead of storage like Dropbox.  So now when a tutor refers a friend they both get another free job request up to a maximum of 20.</p>

<p>It will be interesting to see if this is more effective than money.  My hunch is that it will be - when tutors reach the end of their free account, the conversation in their head is much more around how to get more tutoring jobs, not how to get $3.  What do you think?</p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Your Website To #1 In Google With Seoaholic.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/get-your-website-to-1-in-google-with-seoaholic-com/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-28T22:59:46-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/get-your-website-to-1-in-google-with-seoaholic-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Edit:</strong> Seoaholic has since be re-branded and re-launched as <a href="http://inboxseo.com/?q=1">InboxSeo.com</a>.</p>

<p>This is an exciting announcement.  For the last few months I've been working on a new web app (was contracted to build it actually) and today is the beta launch!</p>

<p>The site is <a href="http://seoaholic.com">Seoaholic.com</a>.  The name is a made up word which combines SEO (search engine optimization) and "work-a-holic".</p>

<p>This is a beta launch so the tool is still a work in progress, but feel free to try it out and send me any feedback on what you like and don't like.</p>

<p><strong>The main benefit of this tool is to bring more traffic to your website by:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Building more incoming links to your site</p></li>
<li><p>Improving your search engine rankings</p></li>
<li><p>Tracking your keyword rankings over time to see big picture SEO changes to your site</p></li>
</ul>


<p>As you may know, building incoming links to your website is one of the best ways to improve your search engine rankings.  Seoaholic goes out to find "link opportunities" for you and ranks them by (1) how valuable the link would be if you got it (2) how likely you are to actually get a link from that site.  Seoaholic helps you (and your team) track the process of getting incoming links from those website owners.</p>

<p>A link opportunity is typically a page on a website that is <em>already linking</em> to your competitors or related websites, but they aren't linking to you yet.  It might be a blog post, a list of resources, job posting board, etc.  You have a good chance of getting a link from these pages because they are already linking to sites like yours (by good I mean maybe 25% chance of success instead of 1% like most link building campaigns).  The last step is still up to you: contact the website owner to ask for a link, submit your site (if their site allows it), or write an interesting piece of content they would be likely to link to.  This last step is standard linking building stuff, and remains a manual process (we don't want this to turn into a spamming tool).</p>

<p>The tool manages the rest for you (finding the high value opportunities, checking if they actually linked, managing your team's progress, and seeing how it ultimately affects your rankings).  We imagine it being used by anyone from small time bloggers (who want to improve and track their search engine rankings over time) to hardcore SEO consultants who do this for a living.</p>

<h2>Here Is A 90 Second Demo Video</h2>

<p>If you don't see the video embedded below (i.e. you're reading this in email) you can <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q7U-aUIR9JA">click here to watch it on YouTube</a>.  Click the "full screen" button below to get a better view or try it in HD.</p>

<h2>And Here Are A Few Screen Shots (Click The Screenshot To See A Larger Version)</h2>

<ol>
<li>Discover new link opportunities and manage the link building process from one screen.</li>
</ol>


<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/01/screen1.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/01/screen1.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<ol>
<li>Track your website's average search engine position over time plus total incoming links</li>
</ol>


<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/01/screen2.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/01/screen2.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<ol>
<li>Watch your individual keyword rankings vary and spot big picture SEO changes to your site</li>
</ol>


<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/01/screen3.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/01/screen3.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<h2>Try It Now For Free...</h2>

<p>The first 5 keywords you want to track and build links for are absolutely free!  To try it out with your website just <a href="http://seoaholic.com">click here to sign up in 30 seconds</a>.</p>

<p>Feel free to leave me any comments or feedback in the comments below!</p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Early Adopters: 5 Ways To Get Users To Your New Website]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/early-adopters-5-ways-to-get-users-to-your-new-website/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-17T16:11:28-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/early-adopters-5-ways-to-get-users-to-your-new-website</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So you just built the next great web app, the launch day has finally come and .... silence.  Crickets chirping.  <strong>You anxiously check your Google Analytics stats and see that despite having the coolest new website ever, nobody seems to care.</strong> More precisely, nobody knows about it yet.</p>

<p>This is one of the toughest moments for entrepreneurs (especially engineering types) when you realize that building the whole thing was the easy part.  Now it's actually marketing the damn thing that is going to take a while.</p>

<p>Here are 5 ways I've used to launch a website and get the first users to my site.</p>

<h2>1. Target Your Niche On StumbleUpon</h2>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/Picture-61.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/Picture-61.png" alt="Stumbleupon" /></a></p>

<p>Stumbleupon has a tech savvy base of people who are looking for cool websites just like yours.  When they are bored, they check Stumbleupon to see what cool new stuff has just been launched.</p>

<p>What's great is that you can target the exact group who might be interested in your site.  For example, with <a href="http://BuyersVote.com">BuyersVote.com</a> I knew people into consumer info and possibly bargains would like the site, and I was able to target those groups.</p>

<p><strong>Pros:</strong> Only $0.05 per visitor (way less than Adwords).  Can target people with relevant interests.  Can see a feedback report afterwards with what percent of people liked/disliked it.</p>

<p><strong>Cons:</strong> Stumbleupon users are pretty click happy and are just trying to prevent boredom, so they tend to have a high bounce rate.  But then again, aren't most web users?  This is a good test to see if your homepage is grabbing people's attention.</p>

<h2>2. Tell people your competition sucks</h2>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/Picture-8.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/Picture-8.png" alt="Facebook" /></a></p>

<p>If you're making a cheaper/better/faster alternative to an existing product, why not tell people that your competitor sucks?  Use their name right in the headline.  These ads tend to have a high click through rate, and your ideal early adopter is someone who is currently using the competition and is fed up.</p>

<p>Facebook ads work well for this, and their ad targeting is outstanding, but it can work elsewhere also like in Adwords or blog posts.  You may recall I launched <a href="http://FeedmailPro.com">FeedmailPro.com</a> because I was fed up with Aweber and thought <a href="http://brianarmstrong.org/posts/my-next-project/">they sucked</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Pros:</strong> Works best when going against an established competitor.  Usually gets a high click through rate.</p>

<p><strong>Cons:</strong> Sometimes you'll run into problems using a trademark in your ad headline and Facebook or whoever will take it down.  But if it happens no biggie, you just take it down or reword it.  Better to ask for forgiveness than permission.</p>

<h2>3. Try to rank for long tail keywords</h2>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/Picture-92.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/Picture-92.png" alt="Long tail" /></a></p>

<p>Traffic from organic search results is free, and 98% of people don't click the ads when doing a Google search - they use the organic search results.  So obviously, ranking in search engines is great.  The problem is it's very difficult for a brand new website.</p>

<p>The solution?  Target <strong>long tail keywords</strong> first - keywords which are more specific, have more words, are more obscure, etc.  One good way to make a long tail keyword is to add a city name or regional keyword on the end.</p>

<p>For <a href="http://www.UniversityTutor.com">UniversityTutor.com</a> this is exactly what I did.  I had a couple dozen subjects (algebra, chemistry, Spanish, etc) and a bunch of cities (Austin, Boston, San Jose, etc) with tutors signed up.  So I combined the subject and the city name (and added 'tutor' in the middle) to auto-generate a bunch of long tail keywords, such as "calculus tutor Austin, TX".  Then I auto-generated pages on the site that targeted those.  Within a few weeks I was getting 500 visitors per day (for free) from organic search results.</p>

<p>Even a brand new site can rank for long tail keywords with just on-page SEO.  If you can start getting traffic for long tail results, then you have early adopters who will eventually give you links, and you'll eventually rank for more competitive keywords too (although this takes a while).  Oh yeah, and don't forget to create a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Site_map">sitemap</a> after you do this so Google actually finds the new pages.</p>

<p><strong>Pros:</strong> Free!  Brings lots of traffic.</p>

<p><strong>Cons:</strong> You need at least SOME good content on the pages for this to work.  It can be user-generated if your users are submitting content (this is best), otherwise you'll have to generate it yourself.</p>

<h2>4. Seed your site using Mechanical Turk</h2>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/Picture-10.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/Picture-10.png" alt="Mechanical Turk" /></a></p>

<p>Amazon's <a href="https://www.mturk.com">Mechanical Turk</a> is awesome, and some entrepreneurs are using this to seed content on their sites.  Basically you create a simple task that can be completed by a human being (write a review, tag this image, vote this up or down, etc) and assign a very low dollar amount to it (say $0.05 or $0.10).  Then you can publish these to Mechanical Turk and thousands of stay at home moms, bored librarians, and people all over the world will complete your task for a few cents and become early users of your website.</p>

<p>Sure, they are getting paid.  But it can help to generate the initial content on a site, even for the SEO trick mentioned in #3 above.  The task is completely open ended so some people also use it to get people's feedback.  You can make the task something like "try this out and tell me what you like about it and what was confusing about it" if you just want to do user testing.</p>

<p>I tried this on <a href="http://buyersvote.com">BuyersVote.com</a> and the results were pretty good.  The main thing you have to worry about is quality.  You can approve or reject each result that someone completes, and Mechanical Turk lets you adjust some quality controls like their approval rate from past requests and what country they are in, English speaking etc.  I'd say overall about 95% of the work completed was worth keeping, and about 5% needed cleaning up or deleting, which is decent.</p>

<p><strong>Pros:</strong> It's guarantees the person will actually <em>participate</em> in your site instead of just viewing it, unlike the other methods.</p>

<p><strong>Cons:</strong> Keep an eye on quality and clean up any junk that gets posted.  Start small (maybe 10 tasks) and see results before going to 100, 1000, etc.  There is an art to making your task instructions clear for 100% of people.</p>

<h2>5. Have a blog</h2>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/Picture-11.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/Picture-11.png" alt="Blog launch" /></a></p>

<p>I saved the best for last.  Having a blog is both the most powerful and the most long term approach.  It takes years of dedicated work to build up a good <a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2008/01/permission-mark.html">permission asset</a>, but once you do it is worth it's weight in gold.</p>

<p>37Signals launched Haystack.com in the <a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1976-launch-haystack-a-better-way-for-web-designers-to-find-clients-and-for-clients-to-find-web-designers">blog post</a> pictured above.  <strong>Just three days later Haystack.com had thousands of registered users and was generating revenue in excess of $7,000 per month.  Their marketing cost for this was zero.</strong> This was all possible because 37Signals has about 100,000 dedicated readers of their blog.</p>

<p>Joel Spolsky did the same thing when he launched StackOverflow.com with a <a href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/items/2008/09/15.html">blog post</a>.  In the last 6 months it has become the #1 programming website in the world because of the critical mass it achieved from his (and his co-founder's) blog posts.</p>

<p>Bottom line: if you don't have a blog, you should start today because it will almost certainly pay off down the road.</p>

<p><strong>Pros:</strong> It's free.  These early adopters know you and actually care about the site (they aren't being paid) which means they'll probably tell their friends.  This is the most powerful form of marketing you can do.</p>

<p><strong>Cons</strong>: Takes a long time to build a following on a blog.  You can't start a blog just to promote stuff. It has to be a topic you actually care about and would write about even if nobody was reading it (because that's exactly how it will feel for the first year or so).</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>There are a few other methods people use, like scraping competitors data off their site (not recommended from an ethical point of view although it can be effective in some cases) and of course you should definitely email it to your friends, your family, post it on your Facebook profile, etc (it's surprising how many people don't do this first and most obvious step - HotOrNot.com launched just by emailing a few friends and was receiving 2 million page page views per day just a few weeks later).</p>

<p>You might get lucky and have your site blow up without any serious marketing effort on your part, but in my experience (and from talking with other entrepreneurs) this is very very rare.  It's far more likely that, even if you have the coolest product in the world, you'll have to spend just as much time marketing it as you did building it, if not more.  Hopefully these tips help you out!</p>

<p><strong>What techniques did I miss?  Which have worked best for you?  Please post your thoughts in the comments below.</strong></p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
