<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Marketing | Brian Armstrong]]></title>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/categories/marketing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-10T23:18:30-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Armstrong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Something I coded up for fun...]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/something-i-coded-up-for-fun/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-22T02:33:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/something-i-coded-up-for-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I put <a href="http://mybestpic.org">this website</a> together over the last few weeks that I thought you might like.</p>

<p>It's quite simple.  Basically you can hold a "photo contest" and see which photo your friends like best.</p>

<p>Here are a few examples...</p>

<ol>
<li>Choose a photo of yourself.</li>
</ol>


<p><a href="http://mybestpic.org/lTmQAr"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/02/Screen-shot-2011-02-21-at-6.24.24-PM-500x360.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<ol>
<li>Choose artwork or travel photos.</li>
</ol>


<p><a href="http://mybestpic.org/0AbTrQ"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/02/Screen-shot-2011-02-21-at-6.22.17-PM-500x360.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<ol>
<li>For downright silliness.</li>
</ol>


<p><a href="http://mybestpic.org/ac8crN"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/02/Screen-shot-2011-02-21-at-6.23.10-PM-500x360.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I'll do a follow up post in a week or so with more details on the idea and results of the site.  But for now...</p>

<h1><a href="http://mybestpic.org">Try it out</a> and let me know what you think!</h1>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Controversial Is Good Marketing]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/being-controversial-is-good-marketing/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-22T23:34:37-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/being-controversial-is-good-marketing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started thinking about this topic lately.  Here are 3 random examples I've noticed - see if you can draw any conclusions or find others.</p>

<h1>1. Ricky Gervais</h1>

<p>He caused an uproar lately by insulting lots of famous people while hosting the Golden Globes.  Backstory <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=flBFagW5vC8">here</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=flBFagW5vC8"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/01/Screen-shot-2011-01-22-at-2.37.13-PM-500x306.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>There is no doubt he angered a bunch of people.  But did this hurt or help his career?</p>

<p>On the one hand he may not be invited back to host the Golden Globes again next year.  On the other hand, most Americans probably didn't know who he was before this week.  They do now, and his appeal as a comedian just went way up.</p>

<p>Apparently, there are lots of people out there who also think Hollywood is ridiculous and full of itself.  These people rushed to his defense and became loyal fans overnight.</p>

<p><strong>Being polarizing means for every enemy you make you gain a devoted fan.  When you remain neutral and try to appeal to both sides, you offend no one but also aren't remembered by anyone.</strong></p>

<p>He might not have had a fun week, but I bet his career just had a net win.</p>

<h1>2. OkCupid.com</h1>

<p>Their blog seems almost entirely centered on the idea of controversy as a marketing tool.  Here are a few of their headlines lately:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://blog.okcupid.com/index.php/the-real-stuff-white-people-like/">The Real Stuff White People Like</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://blog.okcupid.com/index.php/rape-fantasies-and-hygiene-by-state/">Rape Fantasies and Hygiene By State</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://blog.okcupid.com/index.php/your-race-affects-whether-people-write-you-back/">How Your Race Affects Whether People Write You Back</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:WJ1dKFMXD-AJ:blog.okcupid.com/index.php/why-you-should-never-pay-for-online-dating/+why+you+should+never+pay+for+online+dating&amp;cd=1&amp;hl=en&amp;ct=clnk&amp;gl=us">Why You Should Never Pay For Online Dating</a> (where they argue quite convincingly why most online dating sites are a scam)</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Their posts average probably 500 comments and are massively reposted all over the internet.</p>

<p>However, there is one key difference between their posts and most controversial discussions on the net: <strong>their posts are based on hard data, not opinion</strong>.</p>

<p>The guys behind the blog are huge math nerds, and have a wealth of data at their disposal from the dating site (people fill out profiles etc).  So most of their posts take the tone of "we're not saying this is right or wrong, but here is the truth about what the world is like".</p>

<p>This is a powerful position to come from because if someone wants to disagree they have to argue with your math, and can't appeal to emotion.  So I think there is a good lesson here: <strong>if you're going to be controversial, back it up with hard data.</strong></p>

<h1>3. Apple</h1>

<p>Steve jobs puts it a different way in this classic video where he lays out Apple's marketing strategy.</p>

<p>He says every great brand isn't afraid to stand for something.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vmG9jzCHtSQ"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/01/Screen-shot-2011-01-22-at-3.09.43-PM-500x307.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>"Stand for something" is less pejorative than being controversial, but it's really the same thing.  If you stand for something, then you aren't afraid to disagree and you think the other way of doing it is wrong.</p>

<p>And they live it by building opinionated software and hardware.  Want more than one USB drive on your MacBook air?  Sorry can't have it.  Want a discount Apple computer under $500?  They don't want your business.</p>

<p>I think the lesson here is clear.  <strong>In business, trying to be all things to all people just makes you unremarkable to everyone.</strong> People become loyal fans of companies that stand for something.  By polarizing people you'll wins fans (along with the enemies) and stick in people's minds.</p>

<p>I think a healthy dose of speaking your mind can be a great tool to jumpstart any brand.  What do you think?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
