<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: general, | Avi Tzurel]]></title>
  <link href="http://avi.io/blog/categories/general-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://avi.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-26T14:47:59+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://avi.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Avi Tzurel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[copy all files from a folder into a folder without the confirmation on linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://avi.io/blog/2012/07/31/copy-all-files-from-a-folder-into-a-folder-without-the-confirmation-on-linux/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-31T18:17:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://avi.io/blog/2012/07/31/copy-all-files-from-a-folder-into-a-folder-without-the-confirmation-on-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a developer, there are things that never mind how many times you'll do them, you will never ever remember how to do it exactly without googling for a couple of minutes or looking through the last executed list of commands on the terminal.</p>

<p>For me, one of those things is how to copy all files and folders from source to destination with automatic reply yes to overwrite requests.</p>

<p>Here's how you do it</p>

<p><code>bash
cp -apRv &lt;source_folder&gt;/* &lt;dest_folder&gt;/ --reply=yes
</code></p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>

<p>And #notetoself, no need to google anymore, find it on my blog ;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[run rake task in the background and log to file]]></title>
    <link href="http://avi.io/blog/2012/07/30/run-rake-task-in-the-background-and-log-to-file/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-30T02:16:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://avi.io/blog/2012/07/30/run-rake-task-in-the-background-and-log-to-file</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am working with rake tasks a lot, I love the simplicity of creating one and just running one on the server.</p>

<p>For the real heavy lifting I am using a queue system of course, but when I just want to throw something in the queue for example, I will usually create a rake task for it and run it on one of the servers.</p>

<p>I use quick and dirty <code>puts</code> messages to log the progress.</p>

<p>For example I could have a rake task like this:</p>

<p><code>ruby
User.find_each do |user|
  puts "Going over user: #{user.id}"
  Resque.enqueue(...)
end
</code></p>

<p>To run this on the server, I just ssh into is and then I do <code>screen</code> so when I log out of the server the session will save the process and not kill it.</p>

<p>Then, I run this command:</p>

<p><code>
rake foo:bar  --trace 2&gt;&amp;1 &gt;&gt; log/some_log_file.log
</code></p>

<p>That's it, you can now leave the server and let it do all the work, periodically, you can log in and check the progress just by tailing the file.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
