<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Updates | Brian Armstrong]]></title>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/categories/updates/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-11T21:00:55-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Armstrong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Ribbot.com - build your own Reddit/Hacker News style discussion forum]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/announcing-ribbot-com-build-your-own-reddithacker-news-style-discussion-forum/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-27T22:04:33-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/announcing-ribbot-com-build-your-own-reddithacker-news-style-discussion-forum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I launched a new site about a week ago - <a href="http://ribbot.com">Ribbot.com</a> .  It allows you to create better discussion forums online.</p>

<p><a href="http://ribbot.com"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/11/Screen-Shot-2011-11-26-at-7.27.19-PM-500x377.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>If you've ever used Hacker News, Reddit, StackOverflow, or 37Signals Answers - these are all examples of a new breed of forum that has emerged online and tends to be much better than than traditional forums.</p>

<p>Traditional forums often have low quality discussions, and are a place for a vocal minority to rant online.  Many companies avoid user discussion forums because they're worried about giving people a public place to rant.</p>

<p>Ribbot allows anyone to create one of these new types of discussion forums (like the sites mentioned above) with the following features:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>User voting and reputation</p></li>
<li><p>Threaded comments</p></li>
<li><p>Post and comment ranking algorithms</p></li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://ribbot.com"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2011/11/Screen-Shot-2011-11-26-at-7.27.39-PM-500x377.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>Here's how they work: if someone posts something off-topic or unproductive then they are quickly down-voted by the community, and their content is less likely to be seen.  Likewise, if someone posts something helpful or insightful, they are quickly up-voted by the community and their content is more likely to be seen.  The net result of this is that (with enough users) you are more likely to see good content when you visit the forum, and hopefully contribute some yourself.</p>

<p>Who might want a new forum like this?  You never quite know (and I'm eager to find out) but my hunch is this might be useful for:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Businesses</strong>: most companies would like to have user discussion forums because they are a great way to reduce customer support costs. Instead of having customer support reps answering the same questions over and over, users can answer each other's questions - and those answers become public for all to find later (Ribbot lets you search old content easily).  Traditionally, most businesses have been skittish about user discussion forums because they become a public place for a vocal minority of users to rant (see Google Groups). But I believe this new style of forum with the features mentioned above largely solves this quality problem, and businesses will be more likely to adopt it (or their users will for them).</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Question &amp; Answer sites</strong>: these have become very popular lately (see StackExchange and Quora) but there still isn't an easy way for people to start their own QA site on any topic. StackExchange originally started with this vision but they decided to cut off the long tail of smaller topic sites (a mistake in my opinion). Ribbot would allow any special interest group or company to create their own.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Link aggregation sites</strong>: many community sites have grown up around sharing relevant or interesting links on a particular topic (Hacker News is an example of this where the majority of posts are links to external sites with some discussion around them happening in the comments). These are more oriented around timely "latest news and events" links.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Special interest groups</strong>: these could be around health (people with some particular  condition), sports, hobbies, tech stuff (open source projects), classes &amp; learning, etc.  Basically, anything people are using Google Groups for now could work better on Ribbot.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Ribbot is a good fit for the use cases above because it's customizable.  You can change the terminology of the site to reflect questions and answers, link submissions, posts and comments, or anything you'd like.  You can also allow only certain types of submission (links, posts, questions, etc).  Three other features allow customization (some of these are still under development):</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Themes</strong>: Ribbot supports custom themes (much like Tumblr) which I hope will eventually create many diverse and beautiful sites.  Any designer can share (and sell) a custom theme on Ribbot.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Custom domains</strong>: By default Ribbot gives you a subdomain site (again, like Tumblr). But you will soon be able to host the forum on any custom domain of your choosing.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Monetization options</strong>: Ribbot is completely free if you are ok with some ads on the site. But I wanted a way for forum owners and moderators to monetize their sites and be compensated for their work. So with the paid option (see pricing <a href="http://ribbot.com/pricing">here</a>) you are able to run your own ads and turn a profit. My hope is that a number of forums will generate sufficient traction so that their owners can eventually make it a full time gig. For others, I imagine it could make a nice side income or hobby project.  Many businesses I suspect will keep the paid option and run it entirely without ads - the customer support savings would make it more than worth it.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>In short, I think Ribbot will help people build better discussion forums online across a variety of topics.</p>

<h3>Final notes:</h3>

<p>Ribbot is still in an early beta.</p>

<p>To give Ribbot a try you can <strong><a href="http://support.ribbot.com">visit the Ribbot support forum</a></strong>. This is both the support forum for the site and a demo of the product itself.</p>

<p>As always, <strong>please send me your feedback and first impressions in the support forum or in the comments below</strong>. I always love to hear feedback from people on how/if it can be useful to them (or why it's not).</p>

<p>And finally, you can create your own Ribbot forum <a href="http://ribbot.com">right here on the homepage</a> if you want to try it out.</p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some random udpates...]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/some-random-udpates/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-25T06:13:25-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/some-random-udpates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The launch of our <strong><a href="http://brianarmstrong.org/posts/bitcoin-wallet-for-android/">Bitcoin Wallet</a></strong> app for Android went fairly well.  It got about 800 installs in the first week and <a href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2011/07/bitcoin-android-app/">Wired</a> ran a small piece on it which was pretty cool.  We've also gotten a handful of open source contributions, and the app was translated into Russian, Chinese, and German within the first week!</p>

<p>I've been experimenting with <strong><a href="http://MyBestPic.org">MyBestPic.org</a></strong> a bit here and there with some excellent advice from Gabriel Weinberg and Naseem Hakim.  This was my experiment in inherent virality.  It hasn't gone viral yet but I've been measuring the <a href="http://mybestpic.org/kfactor">k-factor</a> in various tests and learning a lot in the process.  Hopefully some more updates on this soon.</p>

<p>Joyce Hu's <strong><a href="http://thebookr.com/">thebookr.com</a></strong> has been growing nicely and getting some real bookings, so this is huge for her.  I've fixed a few things on the site here and there but for the most part it's off and running nicely now, and I think her business is going to do really well.  Investors, get in early on this one.  She is going to be oversubscribed soon :)</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://www.airbnb.com">Airbnb</a></strong> has been an incredible ride, and I've learned so much from the brilliant people there, making tons of friends already.  I've been heading up their fraud prevention effort and I'm about to launch a big machine learning solution (built entirely in the cloud using the Google Prediction API).  Oh and they just announced their B-round of <a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/venturecapital/2011/07/25/airbnb-from-y-combinator-to-112m-funding-in-three-years/?mod=google_news_blog">funding</a> ($112M).  With press and celebrities in the office weekly (along with our personal chef), this is the definition of what it feels like to work at a hot startup.  Revenue and bookings are growing 30% month over month.</p>

<p>And I finally got a chance to catch up with a few <strong><a href="http://carwoo.com">CarWoo!</a></strong> guys (Tommy and Erik) this weekend in San Francisco for a good old fashioned night on the town.  CarWoo! is doing quite well itself and they've got some big deals in the works.  Always good to keep in touch with these folks, and converse with talented entrepreneurs.  Apparently Erik is driving <a href="http://gallery.viperclub.org/data/500/medium/4794Viper_GTS_ACR_Orange_by_Dan_Berndt_1001a.jpg">this</a> to work now.</p>

<p>Have been doing yoga every week, and rock climbing on Tuesdays.  Can't wait to get back in the office tomorrow...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Great Post By Tony Wright On Cashing Out Of Your Business]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/great-post-by-tony-wright-on-cashing-out-of-your-business/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-03T03:38:58-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/great-post-by-tony-wright-on-cashing-out-of-your-business</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Had the pleasure of meeting Tony recently for lunch.  Really enjoyed this post he put up:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.tonywright.com/2010/rethinking-f-you-money/">http://www.tonywright.com/2010/rethinking-f-you-money/</a></p>

<p>Totally agree that the mythical 6-10% return is not being achieved by many these days, and that the real pay off of selling a business can come from the credibility - not the money.</p>

<p>Definitely food for thought, Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When To Skip The Contracts]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/when-to-skip-the-contracts/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-26T22:49:18-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/when-to-skip-the-contracts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've seen a few startups recently who want to have their customers sign contracts to get started.</p>

<p>The logic being that you can guarantee recurring income for your business (for the length of the contract) or you'll have some recourse if the person fails to pay.</p>

<p>But there are two flaws with this thinking:</p>

<ol>
<li>If your product is actually good, customers will stick around whether you have a contract or not</li>
<li>If the customer owes you less than a few thousand dollars, it's not even worth your time to sue them</li>
</ol>


<p>So if you are left with a contract that you'll never enforce, why even ask for it in the first place?  All you're doing is creating a hurdle to getting new customers to try your product.</p>

<p>Google Adwords is a good example.  Most agreements in the advertising world are still done with paper contracts, but Google decided to let anyone start advertising on Adwords in just a few minutes with no up front cost or contracts.</p>

<p>If you fail to pay your Adwords bill, Google isn't going to sue you for $500.  It's not worth their time.  They simply shut down your Adwords account until you pay your bill.  If two years later you are finally ready to try Adwords again, hey - no hard feelings - you can just pay it and your account is instantly re-enabled.</p>

<p>When I see an internet company asking for contracts up front, it feels like their product must not be very good - otherwise why wouldn't they just let me try it knowing full well I'm likely to stick around?</p>

<p>Brian Armstrong</p>

<p>P.S. I certainly don't mean to imply all contracts are bad.  For independent contractors, real estate, anything involving larger sums of money, etc it can make perfect sense.  But most internet companies are charging relatively small sums of money per person.  </p>

<p>P.P.S. Another way to look at is "what would it cost you if the customer doesn't pay?"  Most internet companies have low marginal costs in their products (ad space, some CPU time, etc).  If you're in a high margin business you can afford to give away all sorts of "free trials" in the form of people not paying after signing up.  It's often worth it just to get your product in the hands of more people.</p>

<p>P.P.P.S.  Most companies (including Google) still make you agree to a "Terms of Service" by clicking a checkbox.  Don't confuse this with a contract though.  The terms of service is usually there to prevent <em>you</em> from suing them, not the other way around, and it's a sufficiently small hurdle that it probably won't affect your signup rates.</p>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/07/contract.jpg"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/07/contract-500x400.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Screen After A User Closes Their Account]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/the-screen-after-a-user-closes-their-account/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-25T00:17:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/the-screen-after-a-user-closes-their-account</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gotta have a little fun with it :)</p>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/07/Screen-shot-2010-07-25-at-12.15.29-AM.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/07/Screen-shot-2010-07-25-at-12.15.29-AM-500x379.png" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
