<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Books | Brian Armstrong]]></title>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-11T21:00:55-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Armstrong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Insights After Touring Zappos.com Headquarters]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/insights-after-touring-zappos-com-headquarters/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-24T07:06:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/insights-after-touring-zappos-com-headquarters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past week I made it over to Henderson, Nevada and took a tour of Zappos Headquarters.  I went with all the folks in the startup I'm working for, just because we thought it would be fun and we liked their approach to business.</p>

<p>I also ended up reading the new book by Zappos CEO, Tony Hsieh, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0446563048?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0446563048">Delivering Happiness</a> which I'd highly recommend.  The story of how Zappos came to be a billion dollar company is filled with many twists and turns, and near death experiences.</p>

<p>I just wanted to jot down a few ideas that stuck with me from the tour and the book:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Customer service = good marketing</strong>
Zappos today is known for having great customer service.  But that wasn't always the case.  When they were nearly bankrupt and had no money for marketing, they decided to reach out to their existing customers in the hopes they'd become repeat customers.  It worked.  Taking a $39 loss on a free pair of shoes might appear to be bad business on the surface.  But when that person told 5 of their friends, it ended up being more cost effective than $39 worth of advertising.</li>
</ol>


<p>This is a powerful idea that your customer service can actually be your best marketing.</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Don't outsource your competitive advantage</strong>
At one point Zappos was relying on manufacturers to drop ship all the products they sold on their site.  This allowed them to carry zero inventory and run a simple business, but the orders only had about 95% accuracy and were slow to ship. It also limited the selection of what products they could sell.</li>
</ol>


<p>At some point they had to make a tough decision: if customer service is what they were all about then they needed to control the entire customer experience from beginning to end.  They made a major shift (and nearly went bankrupt) in the process of starting to keep their own inventory, but it paid off.</p>

<p>It's worth spending some time thinking about what your core competency is and focusing only on that.  Once you decide what it is, you may have to sacrifice in other areas to achieve it - so you can't make <em>everything</em> your focus.  As Jim Collins said, "If you have more than three priorities, you have no priorities".  What are you willing to sacrifice so that you can focus on your competitive advantage?</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Fun &amp; purpose > Money</strong>
Finally, one of the most interesting take aways is that Tony ended up preferring fun and purpose over money.  Even after nearly going broke trying to keep Zappos afloat, he still realized that the money wasn't that important.  He started valuing seemingly unimportant things like hanging out with friends at work or playing pranks around the office as bigger contributors to his happiness than money.</li>
</ol>


<p>This definitely showed during their tour as there were plenty of shenanigans.  It's surprising how once a person's basic needs are met, money starts to become much less important than how they get along with bosses and coworkers.</p>

<p>You can check out <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=63WFjoFiXns">Tony's talk from South by Southwest here</a> and checkout <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0446563048?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0446563048">Delivering Happiness on Amazon</a>.</p>

<p>Thank you Zappos for the tour!</p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0446563048?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0446563048"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/05/Screen-shot-2010-05-23-at-11.50.32-PM.png" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Awesome Books I Read Recently]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/three-awesome-books-i-read-recently/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-01T07:58:50-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/three-awesome-books-i-read-recently</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read a bunch of books over the last 3-4 months.  Many of them were unremarkable, others were pretty good, and three were really outstanding.</p>

<p>Here is a quick write up on the three outstanding ones.</p>

<h2><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0393316041?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0393316041">1. Surely You're Joking, Mr. Feynman! (Adventures of a Curious Character) - by Richard Feynman</a></h2>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0393316041?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0393316041"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/03/Screen-shot-2010-02-28-at-11.38.39-PM.png" alt="" /></a>
This is an auto-biography of Richard Feynman, the Nobel Prize winning scientist, who worked on the atom bomb in the 40's (amongst other things).  From that description alone I thought it might be a pretty academic book, but I was totally wrong.</p>

<p>It was at times laugh out loud funny, and other times made me want to cry.  It's basically just a collection of funny stories from his life, from pranks he used to pull while at MIT, to how he learned to pick up women in bars, to how the army mistakenly diagnosed him as mentally insane, to how he learned to pick the locks on safes containing national secrets for fun.</p>

<p>I think what I liked about this book is that it is a great model for how to live life - he always stayed curious.  Here you have a brilliant guy, by any measure, but you can see how he deals with adversity and setbacks, and learns to just appreciate the little things in life.  He was a renaissance man also, having lived abroad for years in Brazil (a trip which reminded me of my time in Argentina) and he made an effort to learn from many fields outside of physics (art, music, etc).  I was actually really sad when I finished this book because I was starting to look forward to reading it every night.  It just...made me happy.  A book hasn't done that for me in a long, long time.</p>

<h2><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596006624?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0596006624">2. Hacker and Painters: Big Ideas From The Computer Age - by Paul Graham</a></h2>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596006624?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0596006624"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/03/Screen-shot-2010-02-28-at-11.39.53-PM.png" alt="" /></a>
One way to judge a book is by how many "holy shit" moments you have when reading it.  A "holy shit" moment is when something clicks in your head - a connection you hadn't seen before, an articulation of an idea that you always knew to be true but couldn't quite put into words, etc.  A moment that gives you a new perspective on life, and often a practical way you can change something in your life (or business) for the better.  A good book for me might have two or three "holy shit" moments buried in the pages and you have to read the whole book to find them.  Hackers and Painters was averaging about one of these <strong>per page</strong> at times.</p>

<p>The first half of the book is the best.  The collection of essays cover a variety of topics from education to building wealth.  They are deep and fascinating.   Paul Graham is turning into one of my favorite writers.  The writing style of the book is actually similar to Malcolm Gladwell's The Tipping Point and his other books.  I'm actually really surprised after reading Hackers and Painters that it isn't more famous than The Tipping Point or a book like that, because I think it's actually better in many ways.  On thing is for sure, Paul Graham is the MASTER of analogies (summing up an idea by comparing it to an similar one that everyone can relate to) - he uses them liberally and they are very effective in driving his point home.</p>

<p>The second half of the book gets into some more nerdy topics related to computer programming which may not be as interesting to most audiences.  Even as a certified computer science super-nerd I found these slightly less interesting.  But the first half of the book alone makes it worth reading.  I recently got to (sort-of) meet Paul Graham in person at a recent Y-Combinator event, so that was pretty sweet.</p>

<p>If there is an overarching theme to this book (a big if, given the scope) it is to compare the current technology renaissance in Silicon Valley to the 15th century artistic renaissance in Florence, and how they both changed the world.</p>

<h2><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0452011876?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0452011876">3. Atlas Shrugged - by Ayn Rand</a></h2>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0452011876?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0452011876"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/03/Screen-shot-2010-02-28-at-11.41.11-PM.png" alt="" /></a>
I decided to read this book after listening to an interview with Jimmy Wales (the founder of Wikipedia) where he described this as one of the books that most influenced him.</p>

<p>It did not disappoint.  On the one hand this book is a masterful piece of fiction that can hold its own amongst the best.  Ayn Rand's writing is like poetry at times (albeit 1,000 pages of it) as she beautifully describes the interaction between characters.  To top it off, the main character, Dagny Taggart, is possibly the strongest (and sexiest) female character I have ever come across in fiction.  The fact this was written in the 50's makes it even more impressive.</p>

<p>But the book is not famous for being a work of fiction.  It has a very strong motive underneath: to convince you of something important (and controversial) about how the world works.  I won't give away exactly what it is - that would spoil the surprise of reading it - but there is no doubt this book is polarizing.  People typically come away either absolutely loving it or absolutely hating it.</p>

<p>I definitely came out more in the former camp of loving it, but I needed little convincing about its message.  The book is not without its faults either - there is a rather preachy diatribe toward the end which I thought was a bit long winded, and at 1,000 pages it certainly isn't an easy read.  Also, Rand's philosophical roots show through in her arguments at times which could be viewed as overly-intellectual (and thus unconvincing) by some audiences.  But given the number of people who list this amongst their favorite (and most influential) books of all time, I think it's something everyone should read.</p>

<p>The weird thing is that this book seems to change you permanently after reading it.  It's almost like being able to "see the matrix" after reading it (just as Neo did in the movie) because it gives you a new lens through which to see the world.  For weeks (and now months) after reading this I keep thinking about it as I overheard little pieces of conversation or discussions on the radio.  I also feel like I have entered a secret society of people who have read (and subscribe to the ideals of) this book.  They identify each other discreetly, but we know who each other are when we cross paths.</p>

<p>Anyway, check them out and let me know what you think!</p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Books For Entrepreneurs]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/the-best-books-for-entrepreneurs/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-04T15:02:59-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/the-best-books-for-entrepreneurs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes I post up <a href="http://brianarmstrong.org/posts/how-to-generate-word-of-mouth-for-your-business/">reviews</a> of books I've enjoyed.</p>

<p>But I think it'd be interesting to get a collective approach from all the readers of this blog.  What books on business have had the greatest impact on you?  Which book do you find yourself recommending to other entrepreneurs the most?</p>

<p>A bunch of suggestions have already been added to BuyersVote.com.  What would you add or subtract?  You can <a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-books-for-entrepreneurs-reviews">check out the list here</a> to add your two cents.</p>

<p><a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-books-for-entrepreneurs-reviews"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/10/Picture-2.png" alt="Picture 2" /></a></p>

<p>In case you've never used BuyersVote.com before, here is a quick review of how it works (it's really simple):</p>

<ul>
<li><p>If you like an item, vote it up (+1)</p></li>
<li><p>If you don't like an item, vote it down (-1)</p></li>
<li><p>If you have a better idea, add it at the bottom</p></li>
</ul>


<p>You'll have to <a href="http://buyersvote.com/user_session/new">login</a> to vote (sorry, that is the only way I could find to keep voting fair), but you can use your Google account or one you already have so there is no registration process.</p>

<p>This isn't really related, but another category that I put together recently on BuyersVote is for the <a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-halloween-costume-ideas-2009-reviews">best halloween costume ideas of 2009</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-halloween-costume-ideas-2009-reviews"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/10/Picture-12.png" alt="Best Halloween Costume Ideas 2009" /></a></p>

<p>As you can see, some of them are good, some are bad (maybe even offensive).  But this is the beauty of crowd sourced data.  Good ideas get pushed to the top and bad ideas get pushed down (with enough participants).</p>

<p>I actually have an ulterior motive for this category: I'm hoping to get on the first page of Google for keywords related to Halloween costume ideas this season!  There will obviously be quite a bit of traffic over the next month for those keywords and, if it works, some new people will be introduced to BuyersVote that wouldn't have otherwise seen it.  This is a nice little marketing technique that you might want to try: target a highly specific seasonal keyword.  If you can get on the first page of Google for it, you might be able to ride a nice wave of traffic that few other people are competing for.</p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Generate Word Of Mouth For Your Business]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/how-to-generate-word-of-mouth-for-your-business/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-20T16:50:15-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/how-to-generate-word-of-mouth-for-your-business</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>About a week ago I met up with another entrepreneur here in Buenos Aires named Eric Northam (he is running a cool software-as-a-service business down here called <a href="http://EasyBroker.com">EasyBroker.com</a> - check it out if you get a chance).</p>

<p>He loaned me a book to read while I was down here, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1427798613?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1427798613">Word Of Mouth Marketing</a>, since I'm a little bit short on English reading material.  The book turned out to generate some good ideas.  Below are my notes while reading it.  At the end I posted some ideas it generated for my business.  Maybe it will help you out too.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1427798613?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1427798613"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/09/Picture-5.png" alt="Picture 5" /></a></p>

<p><strong>My notes...</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>90% of WOM marketing happens offline, people mentioning you in passing to friends and colleagues.  We focus on the 10% that happens online because it's easier to measure and track, but remember it's only 10%.</p></li>
<li><p>It's easy to lose track of how important WOM marketing is.  We think of lead generation in terms of things we pay for (like Adwords) but since WOM is free we often don't realize how many of our new customers came from it.</p></li>
<li><p>give a weird perk to customers, ex. <a href="http://brianarmstrong.org/posts/the-most-awesome-car-wash-of-all-time/">water guns at the car wash</a>, free drinks at the barbershop, enterprise car rental offers to pick you up.  People will talk about it and remember it, it sticks in their head.</p></li>
<li><p>WOM works against you if you suck</p></li>
<li><p>no ad will convince someone if they have heard through WOM that you suck</p></li>
<li><p>be known for something, like the 7 inch high corned beef sandwich in new york - nobody actually needs a 7 inch sandwich, but it's memorable so it gets repeated to tourists who are looking for something to do</p></li>
<li><p>stop buying ads, thrill your customers and they'll advertise for you</p></li>
<li><p>be funny, White Castle let people reserve tables for Valentines Day</p></li>
<li><p>give people metrics to show off to their friends</p></li>
<li><p>you can screw up WOM by offering to pay people for it, when the person gets to your website and finds out their friend got paid for it, the recommendation feels less sincere</p></li>
<li><p>search engines only pull one link from the New York Times, but they pull hundreds from blogs, individuals now have the power to talk about you and get noticed, individuals (as a whole) are more important than major media now</p></li>
<li><p>search engines are going to be death to bad companies (side note: why hasn't this happened already? tons of bad companies still exist - reviews are still too spread out all over the internet in blog comments and forum posts - they don't have the impact they should, this is one thing I wanted to fix with <a href="http://buyersvote.com">BuyersVote.com</a>, consolidating reviews into one simple number)</p></li>
<li><p>marketing is what you DO now, not what you say will do.  people will report on what really happened</p></li>
<li><p>if the first couple reviews for a new product on Amazon are negative, it can kill the entire product</p></li>
<li><p>cheap call centers, giving unpaid bills to collection agencies - these steps which companies take to be more profitable are actually going to start hurting them as word of mouth gets recorded online - everyone is a watchdog now, reporting on your actions</p></li>
<li><p>happy customers are the best advertising (cheaper and more effective than Google Adsense)</p></li>
<li><p>advertising is the tax you pay for having an unremarkable product</p></li>
<li><p>negative WOM is an opportunity for you to fix something and show you care</p></li>
<li><p>put a "Tell A Friend" link on every page of your website</p></li>
<li><p>give free food (a weird one) when customers are waiting in line</p></li>
<li><p>remarkable packaging helps start conversations as people carry it around town, make people ask them "what did you just buy?"</p></li>
<li><p>your best WOM customer could be your newest customer, not the one who has been around a while</p></li>
<li><p>every time someone emails you with a problem it's an opportunity.  Go out of your way to do AWESOME customer support and they'll tell a few people.  The bar is set pretty low since people are used to terrible call centers.</p></li>
<li><p>You have to become known for something.  Something that is short and simple that people can repeat in casual conversation.  Like "Enterprise, they'll pick you up" or "go to Joe's sandwhich shop, they've got the biggest meatball sub in New York" or "Have you tried Pandora?  It builds a radio station just for you".</p></li>
<li><p>Try filling in the blanks about your business: You should really try <strong><strong><strong><em>, it's </em></strong></strong></strong>__.</p></li>
<li><p>There should not be an 'and' in the blank.  Lists don't work...it's friendly, affordable, and fun.  It has to be one simple thing, like "they give you free ice cream while you wait".</p></li>
<li><p>Don't underestimate the power of doing something silly.  Duct Tape brand has a contest where high schools students make prom dresses and tuxedos out of duct tape.  People talk about it.  Pictures get forwarded around the internet and to relatives.</p></li>
<li><p>Progressive insurance gives you the prices of competitors, even if they're lower.  Risky right?  Well, no...customers were probably looking at competitors prices anyway, but it's remarkable they do it so they get word of mouth.</p></li>
<li><p>Don't be so professional and show some personality, like Google's "I'm feeling lucky" button.  Or Facebook let's you change your language to talk like a <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/09/19/once-again-facebook-owns-talk-like-a-pirate-day-on-the-web/">pirate</a>.  Be weird.</p></li>
<li><p>Give people a free postcard at your hotel (with your Hotel's name on it).  They needed to send one to their relatives anyway and will happily use yours.</p></li>
<li><p>On your "tell a friend" form, make sure it allows for multiple recipients.  Also make sure the message comes from the referrer, not your website.  They don't know who you are, but they'll open a message from their friend.</p></li>
<li><p>YouTube got popular (at least in part) because on every single page they ask people to "Share This Video" and embed it in their own website.</p></li>
<li><p>Hotmail went from 0 to 8 million users in less than two years.  How?  They included a short line at the end of every email "Get Your Free Email From Hotmail".  Possibly the most pure WOM product of all time.</p></li>
<li><p>Skype spread by WOM because if you wanted the call to be free, the other person had to install Skype too.  Same thing with Fax machines.</p></li>
<li><p>If you ship products, put something unusual in every box you ship.  Like a bag of M&amp;Ms, or a coupon people will hand out.  Or a note asking if they'll leave you a review on Amazon.</p></li>
<li><p>If you're going to give away swag (free t-shirts, cups, etc).  Make them cool and stuff that people will actually use.  Can't tell you how many free t-shirts I've seen that are extra large and I will never wear.</p></li>
<li><p>You should have a blog (duh).  It takes time to build it up, but it's an essential tool today.  It is the modern day resume.  If people can't find what you've done or what you are doing in your career online, it seems less important.  Choose your name as the domain name, if you are doing anything important people are going to Google you.</p></li>
<li><p>Include "easter eggs" in your products.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Some Ideas It Generated For My Businesses</strong></p>

<p>So as I was reading, I would take a few minutes to think about how each idea applied to my various web businesses.</p>

<p>BuyersVote.com is a naturally viral product because it ranks things.  Whenever you claim something or someone is better or worse, it generates controversy and gets people's attention.  So I came up with some ideas to help multiply this effect.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Make an "awards" page with the highest and lowest rated items across the entire site.  You could also do best and worst this year, and month also.  This could definitely generate some WOM if people could say "did you see XYZ was the worst rated company of all time?" or "We had the top rated product on BuyersVote this month!"  If you loved the company you'd go there to defend it.  If you hated the company you'd go there to throw gas on the fire.</p></li>
<li><p>Make some badges, little images, that people could display on their site.  They could say thing "top rated cell phone of 2009 on BuyersVote.com" or something like that.</p></li>
<li><p>Make some swag at CafePress.com like maybe a t-shirt that said "Careful, I'll be rating your performance on BuyersVote.com".</p></li>
<li><p>Let people Tweet their reviews out!</p></li>
</ul>


<p>This last one was quite simple to do, so I actually threw it together and it's now live on the site.  People can tweet their reviews!  When you're signed in a little link like this will appear:</p>

<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/09/Picture-31.png" alt="Picture-3" /></p>

<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/09/Picture-4.png" alt="Picture 4" /></p>

<p>For UniversityTutor.com I was thinking about swag I could send to tutors...t-shirts, coffee cups, etc.  But none of these sounded very exciting.  Then I had an interesting idea: what about business cards?</p>

<p>I have a feeling tutors would actually use these because business cards are new and cool for college students (you probably haven't gotten them before) and if you had them in your dorm room, your friends would probably ask you about them.  I wouldn't be able to send them to all tutors obviously, but for paying tutors perhaps it would be a worthwhile investment.  How much could it cost to send 250 business cards to a paying tutor?  Maybe less than $10, which is what they pay in their first month.  So it would break even quickly and help generate WOM.  I'd have to investigate this further and see what companies out there could make this process really easy.</p>

<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>

<p>The book was quite simple and an easy read.  It didn't tell me anything earth shattering that I didn't already know, but at the same time it was very helpful in generating some ideas while I was reading it.  If you'd like to check out the book on Amazon you can see it <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1427798613?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1427798613">here</a>.</p>

<p>I'd love to hear your thoughts in the comments about WOM.  Which of these techniques do you think has the most potential?  Which have had the greatest effect in your business?</p>

<p>Finally, just for fun here is a picture of my "office" in Buenos Aires where I spend an average work day.  Pretty tough life, right?</p>

<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/09/8319_547723136311_3002642_32395765_6245859_n.jpg" alt="8319_547723136311_3002642_32395765_6245859_n" /></p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Releasing Breaking Free, the eBook, For Free]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/releasing-breaking-free-the-ebook-for-free/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-11T20:15:27-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/releasing-breaking-free-the-ebook-for-free</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Breaking Free, the <a href="http://www.startbreakingfree.com/breaking-free/">book</a>, came out a few years ago when this blog started.  Since then it has done reasonably well (for a first time author) both in print and online.  But something happened a while after it came out: I started to wish I'd given the electronic version away for free and only charged for the print copies.</p>

<p>After all, there were a number of online free eBooks that had come out that I'd really enjoyed and had been successful, like <a href="http://gettingreal.37signals.com/">Getting Real</a>, the <a href="http://charliehoehn.com/2009/07/14/announcing-my-first-e-book/">Recession Proof Grad</a>, and a number of <a href="http://superaff.com/archives/2006/02/15/the-master-list-of-seth-godins-free-ebooks/">Seth Godin's</a> works.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.startbreakingfree.com/breaking-free/"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/09/bookImage.jpg" alt="Breaking Free Brian Armstrong" /></a>To many people it might seem counter-intuitive to release a book for free, but things are changing in the digital age.  Much electronic content can be shared online at zero cost, and the distribution cost of an eBook has come down to zero.  So some authors find it useful as a means to build their brand, spread an idea, etc - things which can be much more valuable than book sales.  And in many cases (Getting Real being one example) it turned out they sold MORE paper copies as a result of releasing the eBook for free.  People liked what they read online and wanted a "dead tree" version to read the rest more easily, mark up with notes, share with a friend as a gift, or just say thank you.</p>

<p>Of course, the biggest problem this presented in my case is that I'd already been selling the eBook version for some time, and people would be upset if I decided to release it now for free.  So I pondered this for a while and came up with a solution that isn't perfect but I hope will be a valid compromise: if you purchased an electronic copy in the past and would like a refund now that it's free, simply <a href="http://www.startbreakingfree.com/contact/">contact me</a> and I'll send it right over with my sincere apologies.  It's been out for two years now and sales have started to slow, so I figured if I was going to do it the time was now.  I also decided it should be done in a totally open and transparent way with a blog post.  To be honest, my hope is that most people who bought it found it worth purchasing a year or two ahead of other people (the emails I get tend to indicate that is the case) but if not I am more than happy to eat the cost for my mistake in not making it free from the beginning.  This was a really hard decision to make actually, and I wish I'd gotten it right from the beginning so this wasn't necessary.  But I didn't, so hopefully this will make the best of an unfortunate situation.</p>

<p>On the plus side, this will hopefully make the ideas in the book available to a much wider audience and build readership to the blog over time.  I've updated the book's <a href="http://www.startbreakingfree.com/breaking-free/">page on this blog</a>.  And if you haven't already, please feel free to check it out.</p>

<p>And if you're upset by this as someone who purchased it in the past, I totally understand.  Feel free to <a href="http://www.startbreakingfree.com/contact/">contact me</a> for a refund and I'll make it right.<a href="../contact/">
</a></p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
