<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: FeedmailPro.com | Brian Armstrong]]></title>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/categories/feedmailpro-com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-11T14:36:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Armstrong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shutting Down FeedmailPro.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/shutting-down-feedmailpro-com/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-24T05:19:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/shutting-down-feedmailpro-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Had a bit of a sad moment today as I finally shut down FeedmailPro (or at least began the transition process to do so).</p>

<p>I'd been contemplating this move for a while, and finally bit the bullet.  Why?  Well the short answer is that I don't have enough time to work on it, and it never took off the way I'd hoped.  Actually, Email Service Providers have gotten a lot better since I created FeedmailPro (the narcissist in me would like to think I had something to do with that - pushing the competition in the right direction - but it's probably totally unrelated).</p>

<p>Since I created it, 800 blogs have come to depend on it (albeit only 20 were paying customers) so clearly, communicating this news to the users of FeedmailPro is no small task.  I fully expect to upset some people in doing this, but there is definitely a right and wrong way to go about doing it.  Probably the biggest thing I was able to do was setup an excellent transition process for all the users to move over to MailChimp.  So hopefully this will be a step in the right direciton.  Below I've included some excerpts from <a href="http://feedmailpro.com/mailchimp">the page I created on FeedmailPro</a> to explain the transition to all the users.</p>

<p>I also made an effort give as much transparency as possible on the page.  I spoke in the first person and used the words "I'm sorry" (as opposed to "<a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1528-the-bullshit-of-outage-language">we apologize for any inconvenience</a>" or hedging language like that).</p>

<p>The transition page is displayed below.</p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free (even when it means making difficult decisions),
Brian Armstrong</p>

<p>P.S. If you are ever facing a similar dilema on sticking with a project or dropping it, one of my favorite books on the subject is Seth Godin's <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1591841666?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1591841666">The Dip: A Little Book That Teaches You When to Quit (and When to Stick)</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=httpwwwstartb-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1591841666" alt="" />.</p>

<p>=================================================================</p>

<h1>FeedmailPro Is Closing!</h1>

<p>On December 1st, 2010, FeedmailPro will permanently shutdown and stop sending email.</p>

<p>It's recommended for all current FeedmailPro customers to export their data and transition their email lists over to <a href="http://www.mailchimp.com/signup/h?pid=feedmailpro&amp;source=website">MailChimp</a>, who we are working with to handle this transition.</p>

<p>This page will try to answer any questions you may have about the change, and assist you in the transition process.</p>

<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/10/transfer-500x97.png" alt="" /></p>

<h3>Why is FeedmailPro closing?</h3>

<p>First just let me say: I'm sorry.  I realize closing FeedmailPro will inconvenience a large number of people, so I want to be as candid as possible in explaining the sudden closure.</p>

<p>The main reason is that as a sole developer, I no longer have time to work on the site.  It started as a side project to meet my own needs, and has since grown beyond my ability.  With a full time job and another larger startup to run, I was lucky to work even a few hours a month on FeedmailPro.</p>

<p>Although over 800 blogs are now using FeedmailPro, only about 20 of those ever reached the threshold of needing to pay for the service.  Therefore, with a total revenue of around $200 per month I can't justify the amount of time it takes to maintain and run the site.  This may have been a miscalculation on my part in the business model (this whole thing has been a learning experience business wise, and I've certainly made some errors along the way).</p>

<p>Bottom line, I was trying to do too many projects at once, and if I didn't consolidate them a bit I was in danger of doing them all poorly.  Something had to give, and after weighing my options that turned out to be FeedmailPro.</p>

<h3>Can't you leave the site running even if you don't have time to work on it?</h3>

<p>I'd like to do this but unfortunately it is somewhat dangerous to leave a large email server operating entirely on it's own.  There are now over half a million emails in the FeedmailPro database which makes it a target for hackers and spammers.  And mail server reputation fluctuates over time.  If for some reason the server were to be blacklisted I'd have a fairly big emergency on my hands (and potentially lawsuits) that would require lots of work to get fixed (especially with so many people depending on it).  I can't afford to have that liability waiting to strike at any moment given my other responsibilities.</p>

<h3>Could you sell or donate FeedmailPro to someone else to keep it running?</h3>

<p>I contemplated this as well but ultimately decided against it because the internals of FeedmailPro are complex enough that it would be time consuming to bring someone else up to speed.  It's also not a very forgiving system (a small bug could accidentally email millions of people) so it's not a good candidate to pass on to someone who only understood it at a high level.</p>

<p>In addition, the functionality offered by FeedmailPro is now provided by more established service providers (like MailChimp) so there isn't much reason to duplicate the functionality (granted the low cost of FeedmailPro was an important difference, but some steps have been taken to mitigate this - see the question on cost below).</p>

<h3>Why MailChimp?</h3>

<p>I've been tracking their service for a while and simply put, they know what they are doing.  They also have a large team and infrastructure that is capable of handling the sort of volume and potential emergencies that come from running a service like this.  They are a world class Email Service Provider, and they aren't going anywhere.</p>

<p>In fact, with the features they've been adding over the past few years (especially the same 1000 subscribers for free accounts) their service is quite a bit better than FeedmailPro (certainly more full featured), so there is really no reason not to use them.  I suspect their deliverability is also better than FeedmailPro, so this will be a nice bonus when switching over.</p>

<p>I reached out to MailChimp about a month ago when I realized the predicament I was in, and they agreed to assist in the transition of all FeedmailPro customers (even with the large number of free users). They've been great to work with so far which only gives me more confidence in transferring FeedmailPro users to their service.</p>

<h3>What is the schedule for shutting down?</h3>

<p><strong>10/23/2010</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>notice to current FeedmailPro customers of upcoming changes, new accounts no longer accepted on FeedmailPro, service continues for existing customers as usual</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>11/1/2010</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>second notice goes out to all customers about upcoming shutdown</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>11/23/2010</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>final notice of upcoming shutdown</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>12/1/2010</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>no more emails will be sent from FeedmailPro, website will still be accessible to export data</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>1/1/2011</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>last day to access website and export data</li>
</ul>


<p>They key date to remember is <strong>December 1st, 2010</strong>.  You should have your list migrated over to MailChimp by this date to avoid any interruption in service.</p>

<h3>What does MailChimp cost compared to FeedmailPro?</h3>

<p>If you're a free user of FeedmailPro then MailChimp will also be free.  They have the same 1,000 subscriber limit on free accounts.</p>

<p>If you're a paying customer of FeedmailPro (as of 10/22/2010), MailChimp has graciously agreed to "grandfather" you in at the same rate you were paying at FeedmailPro.  This means your price won't change.  Be sure to sign up using the link on this page and try to use the same email address (from your FeedmailPro account) when signing up with MailChimp to make this process as easy as possible.  Note that you may need to sign up with MailChimp at the regular price to get started since the special discount may not be applied right away.  You can email FeedmailPro Support if it still hasn't changed after a few weeks.</p>

<p>All paying customers of FeedmailPro will have their Paypal subscriptions canceled as of 10/23/2010 so you won't be charged again by FeedmailPro after that date.</p>

<h2>Ready to start the transition?</h2>

<p>Head over to <a href="http://www.mailchimp.com/signup/h?pid=feedmailpro&amp;source=website">MailChimp</a> to create your account.</p>

<p>You will need to complete this process <strong>before December 1st, 2010</strong> to ensure there is no interruption in delivery to your subscribers.</p>

<p>Note: if you don't already have a MailChimp account you should sign up using the MailChimp link on this page so they know you are a former FeedmailPro customer.</p>

<p>If possible, please use the same email address to create your account at MailChimp that you used at FeedmailPro.</p>

<h2>Detailed <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=geqF5B1il9c">video walkthrough</a> of the transition process:</h2>

<p>Tip: set to fullscreen and 720p resolution for best viewing experience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kicked out of my own Google Group!]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/kicked-out-of-my-own-google-group/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-14T15:47:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/kicked-out-of-my-own-google-group</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is unfortunate.  I no longer have access to the Google Group I use for support <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/feedmailpro">http://groups.google.com/group/feedmailpro</a> on FeedmailPro.com.</p>

<p>It seems there is a known bug with Groups where people are getting unsubscribed.  This happened to me, which in itself is no big deal.  But when I re-subscribed by emailing the +subscribe address for the group, my ownership of the group disappeared!</p>

<p>This means I can't moderate incoming messages and no new members can be added. The group is currently orphaned, without an owner, and there are pending messages waiting from customers that have gotten no response.  I can't even delete the group to recreate it since I'm no longer the owner.</p>

<p>I've <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/is-something-broken/browse_frm/thread/d3abee6cb34ef1d7/68dea94927a42561?lnk=gst&amp;q=ownership+removed#68dea94927a42561">posted</a> to the Google Groups support forum to see if anyone could help.  But it looks like they are swamped and I haven't gotten any reply.</p>

<p>Googlers, can anyone out there help?  Has anyone had better luck with an alternative platform for Q&amp;A and customer support?</p>

<p>Former Google Group Owner,
Brian Armstrong</p>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/07/Screen-shot-2010-07-14-at-3.34.01-PM.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/07/Screen-shot-2010-07-14-at-3.34.01-PM-300x213.png" alt="" /> </a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FeedmailPro.com Sent Over Half A Million Messages In The Last 6 Months]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/feedmailpro-com-sent-over-half-a-million-messages-in-the-last-6-months/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-16T16:01:56-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/feedmailpro-com-sent-over-half-a-million-messages-in-the-last-6-months</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is pretty cool.  Was looking at the stats recently for FeedmailPro.com and about 600,000 messages (blog posts going to email subscribers) have gone out since it started just six months ago.</p>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/03/mailgraph.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2010/03/mailgraph.png" alt="" />
</a></p>

<ul>
<li><p>306 blogs with 132,844 total subscribers are now using the service</p></li>
<li><p>9 paying customers so far which is a 3% conversion rate on a freemium product</p></li>
</ul>


<p>The main untested theory behind the site, which is that you can let users import subscriber lists without another opt-in by <a href="http://feedmailpro.com/faqs/1">testing the list first</a> seem to be working quite well.  You can weed out spammers without punishing the good guys.</p>

<p>It has also saved people a lot of money who have switched from Aweber.com.  I was previously paying $70 per month to manage the email list for this blog and one other with Aweber, so in the past 6 months FeedmailPro.com has saved me $360 just by switching.</p>

<p>Maybe it can do the same for your blog?  If you're looking for a more versatile email newsletter for your RSS feed (at a fraction of the cost) <a href="http://feedmailpro.com">check out the site</a>.</p>

<p>There is also an <a href="http://feedmailpro.com/faqs/4">affiliate program</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Pieces That Make Up FeedmailPro.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/the-pieces-that-make-up-feedmailpro-com/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-19T18:03:27-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/the-pieces-that-make-up-feedmailpro-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here is an interesting list of the open source pieces that went into making <a href="http://feedmailpro.com">FeedmailPro.com</a>, in no particular order.  Remarkably, they are all free.  Perhaps what's even more remarkable is that I can't think of a paid alternative that I'd rather use in any of these cases, even if it was free.  Open source is great at making reliable code because so many eyeballs get to look at it, tear it apart, and fix weaknesses.  It general, I find it much more reliable than proprietary code.</p>

<p>This list can be a bit intimidating if you're new to this stuff.  Don't worry, you don't need to be an expert in any of these, and in fact <a href="http://www.startbreakingfree.com/go/slicehost/">Slicehost</a> (where I'm hosting the app) has a great bunch of tutorials to help you get through installing the first five or so.  For non-technical people...this may only be interesting as a overview of what goes on behind the scenes, but I thought I'd post it just the same.</p>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/08/98857402_14e9645ed8.jpg"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/08/98857402_14e9645ed8.jpg" alt="98857402_14e9645ed8" /></a>
Photo of the linux penguin in an IBM add - <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/phauly/98857402/">source</a>.</p>

<p><strong>The components:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://www.rubyonrails.org">Ruby on Rails</a>
The is the "web framework" that I used to make the site.  It provides you with a lot of functionality like creating models (subscribers, feeds, etc) and connecting it all to the database.  Many of the tools listed toward the end are "plugins" for Ruby on Rails.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.mysql.com/">MySQL</a>
This is the database running underneath which stores all the data and makes it permanent.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.ubuntu.com">Ubuntu Linux</a>
This is the operating system for the server hosted with <a href="http://www.startbreakingfree.com/go/slicehost/">Slicehost.com</a>.  It's stable, fast, and memory efficient.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://nginx.net/">Nginx</a>
This is the webserver which takes incoming requests from people's web browsers and routes them to my application.  You may have heard of Apache which is a more popular web server.  Nginx is newer on the scene, but I prefer it...faster and less memory intensive.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.modrails.com/">Passenger mod_rails</a>
Keeps lots of "worker" processes busy on the server processing requests, and spawns new ones if the existing ones can't keep up.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.postfix.org/">Postfix</a>
This is the mail server which handles all sending and receiving of email.  It's pretty much the standard in the linux world now and is known for being able to handle extremely high volumes of email.  I'm not sure what capacity I could get up to on my current server before needing to upgrade, but it's probably at least in the millions of emails per day.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.courier-mta.org/">Courier</a>
Handles logins and accounts on the mail server.  I've got accounts for bounces, complaints, unsubscribes, support, etc.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/dkim-milter/">DKIM-Milter</a>
This plugin to Postfix "signs" outgoing emails to verify they originated from my domain.  This helps them get through some spam filters.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://git-scm.com/">GIT</a>
This is a "source control" system where I keep the code I'm writing.  It keeps track of versions and history of the files.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.capify.org/index.php/Capistrano">Capistrano</a>
This is used to "deploy" code from my development machine to the production server.  There are a number of steps each time you change the code to get it on the server, like shutting down what's currently running, cleaning up log files, moving over stuff you want to keep from the last version, starting up the new code, etc.  This lets you do all the steps with one command.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.netbeans.org/">Netbeans</a>
A text editor (and a whole lot more -the fancy word for it is "integrated development environment" or IDE) to write the code on my laptop.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>The rest are all plugins for Ruby on Rails:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://wiki.github.com/mislav/will_paginate">Will_Paginate</a>
This helps you create "pages" - just like on google where there is a "next", "previous", 1, 2, 3....etc links at the bottom.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://github.com/binarylogic/authlogic/tree/master">AuthLogic</a>
Handles the logins, email activation, lost passwords, etc for creating new user accounts.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://rubyforge.org/projects/ruby-openid/">Ruby-OpenID</a>
Let's people login with OpenID instead of a email/password.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://github.com/grosser/rpx_now/tree/master">rpx_now</a>
Similar to above but also lets people use the fancy RPXNow.com widget with the big buttons for Google, Yahoo, etc.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://github.com/pauldix/feedzirra/tree/master">Feedzirra</a>
Library to quickly parse a lot of RSS or ATOM feeds.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://github.com/jnunemaker/columbus/tree/master">columbus</a>
Detects RSS feeds on a website.  This lets people type either the RSS feed directly or their blog URL (in which case columbus will "discover" the feed URL for them).</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://github.com/ryanb/uniquify/tree/master">Uniquify</a>
Library to generate those unique "tokens" you see on the end of URL's.  Like when you click a confirmation link or unsubscribe link, sometimes you'll see a list of random characters on the end of it.  This generates those and makes sure there are no duplicates across your system.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://chronic.rubyforge.org/">Chronic</a>
This helps with some of the scheduling where I let people send out emails one per day, or week, or several times per week, etc.  More specifically it converts human readable time (like "next Thursday") into time that a computer can understand.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://github.com/javan/whenever/tree/master">Whenever</a>
This helps schedule recurring tasks that happen in the background, like parsing feeds, sending emails, checking for bounced emails, etc.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://github.com/tobi/delayed_job/tree/master">delayed_job</a>
This queues tasks to be processed at a later date, such as importing subscribers, or sending mailings.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://github.com/alexvollmer/daemon-spawn/tree/master">daemon_spawn</a>
This tool launches delayed_job in the background (or several of them to run at once if there is high volume).</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://fastercsv.rubyforge.org/">fastercsv</a>
Handles importing and exporting csv files.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://dist.leetsoft.com/api/paypal/">paypal</a> and <a href="http://rubyforge.org/projects/money/">money</a> gems
Handles processing of notifications when something happens over at Paypal, like someone subscribes, unsubscribes, sends a payment, etc.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.activemerchant.org/">active_merchant</a>
Communicates with Paypal to send affiliate payments.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://github.com/rails/exception_notification/tree/master">exception notifier</a>
Lets me know when errors occur on the website.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>So those are all the pieces (might have missed a few but 27 listed here).  There's at least 100,000 lines of code above that I was able to use.  And what did I write?  About 4,000 lines of ruby code that ties it all together.  The user interface is completely new, the models and the logic, but as you can see many of the pieces underneath are modular and can be plugged in to to get the benefit without having to write them from scratch.</p>

<p>If you haven't seen the final product yet, take a second to <a href="http://feedmailpro.com">check it out</a>.</p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Next Project, And Why Aweber Sucks]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/my-next-project/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-27T21:13:54-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/my-next-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>WARNING: this post gets a little geeky talking about a tool for bloggers.  Some of you might not have an interest in it but I thought I'd post it regardless.</p>

<p>About a week ago I was sitting around with nothing super urgent to do.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.universitytutor.com/">UniversityTutor.com</a> has been running on auto-pilot almost 100% with new tutors signing up every day.  I only need to answer about 1 or 2 emails per week on it, especially as the <a href="http://www.universitytutor.com/faq">FAQ</a> page has grown and becomes more complete.  Sure there are a few little things on my list to add for it (for example, about 1 in every 500 tutors who signs up managed to enter an address which doesn't come up in Google maps correctly, and it breaks some stuff.)  But I couldn't get excited about fixing it.  It just didn't affect enough people.</p>

<p>Similarly, <a href="http://buyersvote.com/">BuyersVote.com</a> is in a holding pattern as I wait for Google to index some stuff.  I've been using it quite a bit myself and finding it much easier/faster now to fit into my workflow if I want to add something quickly.  There are actually a bunch of things I'd like to eventually add there too (a demo video for the home page, make the vote-up and vote-down buttons more responsive, maybe a press release to get some PR for it).  People are actually able to <a href="http://buyersvote.uservoice.com">vote</a> on what features they'd like to see next, so I can prioritize them.  But nothing really struck me that day.</p>

<p>So I turned my attention to something that had been bothering me for a while: Aweber.  Aweber is an email newsletter service that lots of bloggers use to offer email subscriptions.  Aweber had been annoying me for a bit.  I use it on <a href="http://homeworkhelpblog.com/">HomeworkHelpBlog.com</a> (the blog for UniversityTutor) and every month it had been costing me more and more.  It was about to reach the point where I was paying $70/month for it, and this was just ridiculous.  That was more than my web hosting, credit card processing, etc combined.  For a simple email newsletter!</p>

<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/07/homeworkhelpblog1.png" alt="homeworkhelpblog" /></p>

<p>Worse still, the user interface to manage your Aweber is horrible and I could never get it to do what I wanted.  The whole site was clearly designed by some very technical people who had no concept of how people would actually use it (and then threw a pretty coat of paint over it).  For example, let's say you were designing an HTML email and you saved some changes on Aweber.  You might want to see how those changes looked before it got sent out to your entire list of thousands of people right?  Well Aweber didn't let you do this (for a blog broadcast).  You have to wait until your next blog post and just hope it looked right.  Or what if you wanted to send out your entire blog posts to people by email (and not just summaries which would piss them off by making them click through to your site).  Well, Aweber didn't offer this and provided an embarrassing hack in their "help" pages which would require you to do extra work on every single future blog post you made.</p>

<p>There were other little things.  Aweber pulls the feed in a way that Adsense for feeds doesn't show up.  They charge you for subscribers who have UNSUBSCRIBED from your feed.</p>

<p>Aweber also prides itself on how there are "real human" beings there to answer customer support calls and brags about this on its site.  This bugged me too - you do realize I don't actually want to EVER call your tech support.  Do you think I enjoy waiting on hold, answering phone prompts, and speaking with people who have no authority to actually fix the problem?  Here is a tip for web businesses: If I ever have to actually pick up a phone to call you for tech support, you've already failed.  If I'm calling it's because you messed up, and your site is broken.  Instead of paying for a huge phone center of support reps - why not just FIX your website.  Look at Gmail, millions of users and not a phone number in sight.</p>

<p>Anyway, so how were they getting away with charging this much for a crappy service?  The answer I think lies in their tiered business model, and the fact that it's very difficult to move your email list.  You can start out with them at a very low price.  And once they have you locked in it keeps going up.  The kicker is that if you ever want to try a different service they make it very difficult for you because all the newsletter companies out there require you to send another "opt-in" email to all your subscribers if you move.  This annoying and confusing email basically ensures you will lose about half your subscribers if you ever move.  So they've got you, and they know it.</p>

<p>A while back I wrote an <a href="http://www.problogger.net/archives/2007/07/03/rss-to-email-comparison-review-feedburner-feedblitz-zookoda-aweber/">article for ProBlogger</a> on this exact topic, and complained about the lack of options out there for bloggers.</p>

<p>So I was sitting there thinking about how I could probably code up my own newsletter service really quickly, and save myself $70/month.  And if I wrote it myself, I wouldn't have to mess with this silly "extra opt-in" business.  Then I started thinking that if I wanted this for myself, maybe other people would want it too.  But then...wouldn't it be a big hassle to open it up to the public, if people started trying to game the system etc and use it for spam or something like that.</p>

<p>So I let it marinate in my brain for a few days until I eventually came up with (what I think is) a great solution to this problem.</p>

<p>Let's say some new user signs up and wants to import their list of 10,000 subscribers from Aweber.  Why not trust them (by default) and test out the list in a programmatic way which doesn't require a manual, human review process (which would never be 100% effective by the way - people can fake credentials if they want).  Why not send the next email to say...10 of those subscribers on the list, and see how many (if any) come back as bounces, complaints, unsubscribes, etc.  If all is well, send the next email to 100, and the next to 1000, and eventually you could be quite confident that the list is valid and start sending to the whole thing.  If flags went up after you first few tests (in the form of lots of unsubscribes, complaints, or bounce) then the person is probably a spammer and you just close their account.  If would be worth it for them to send out 10 or even 100 emails, when they deal in millions of emails.  The whole process would take less than a week or two (however fast they sent out 4 blog posts) and the cool part is that none of the subscribers would actually have to "miss" an email.  The ones who got later emails would just have more posts in those emails until the "import" process was done.</p>

<p>If that worked...then the rest wouldn't be too hard.  Make a user interface that actually, worked.  Let people test their emails, import their list from whatever crappy provider their using now.  Get rid f tired pricing and make the service a flat $10/month with the first 1000 subscribers free (the real cost to run this is almost nothing if you don't have huge phone support centers and a broken site).  It would be a freemium business model that would save people a ton of money over Aweber.</p>

<p>Then if I built it, I'm pretty sure I could get Darren to let me do another post on ProBlogger (which has over 100,000 readers - all bloggers, many of whom use Aweber).  This would be an easy to launch the product to a ton of people.  I could also set up a nice affiliate program so every blogger who tried it would probably blog about it to others...and wow, this could turn into a nice little business.  Maybe a week or two of work to build it.</p>

<p>So anyway, that's what I've been working on the last week or so.  I should have a prototype out for you to look at later this week (you'll hear about it first here if you want to be a beta tester).  Some of the technical issues involved with running a mail server and the Can Spam Act are quite technical, but I don't think it's anything I can't handle.  I'm already running my own mail server for UniversityTutor and it hasn't been too bad.</p>

<p>I could probably do an entire other post on the technical aspects I've gotten into actually.  One cool part is that I'm modularizing the server which actually is going to do the mass mailing.  The reason why this is cool is that if a problem ever does happen and the mail server does get black listed due to a bug in the code or malicious users, etc, I can literally just spawn a new server with a new IP in 5 minutes and have a clean server.  I can also clone/spawn new mail servers on the fly to keep up with demand if this thing gets huge overnight.  In this sense they are like worker processes, totally separate from the main server with the database and serving up the homepage, etc.  Workers can get killed off without the whole machine coming down.</p>

<p>Suffice to say I think it's gonna be awesome.  I'll send you link to try it out later this week!</p>

<p>Hopefully it will be a nice addition to my "portfolio" of sites out there, running on auto-pilot.</p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
