<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: MongoDB | Avi Tzurel]]></title>
  <link href="http://avi.io/blog/categories/mongodb/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://avi.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-22T17:01:50+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://avi.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Avi Tzurel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real life usage for mongoexport (and a bonus)]]></title>
    <link href="http://avi.io/blog/2013/11/22/export-mongo-collection-to-json-with-query/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-22T16:39:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://avi.io/blog/2013/11/22/export-mongo-collection-to-json-with-query</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I work a lot with MongoDB, and this is not the "Why not MongoDB" or "Why MongoDB" type of post, I know it's popular to trash Mongo lately.</p>

<p>Anyway, while working with Mongo, from time to time I need to export a collection, or a subset of the collection based on a query.</p>

<p>I love using <code>mongoexport</code> because you basically get JSON file out of it (or CSV) and from there on you can pretty much do anything you want with it.</p>

<p>You can use Amazon's MapReduce or any other solution you may want.</p>

<p>For example, when I do usually is export a list I need, load it into Rails console and work with the output, queue it up to the worker list etc...</p>

<p>Let's cover some scenarios I use the most</p>

<h2>Export Collection To JSON</h2>

<p>Actually, I never use it, since the collections are too big for the disk to handle at once, we have a sharded collection, so no one-disk solution can hold the data.</p>

<p>That been said, I think for most people this can be very useful.</p>

<p><code>
mongoexport --host HOST --port PORT --db DB_NAME -u USERNAME -p PASSWORD --collection COLLECTION_NANE -q '{}' --out YOUR_FILENAME.json
</code></p>

<h2>Export part of the collection to JSON (using a query)</h2>

<p><code>
mongoexport --host HOST --port PORT --db DB_NAME -u USERNAME -p PASSWORD --collection COLLECTION_NANE -q '{ "some_numeric_field": { "$gte": 100 } }' --out YOUR_FILENAME.json
</code></p>

<p>The most important part here is that the -q options needs to be a valid JSON format query that Mongo knows how to handle <code>{ "some_numeric_field": { "$gte": 100 } }</code>. You can of course use far more complicated queries, but for most cases I don't need to.</p>

<h2>Bonus</h2>

<p>I use <a href="http://kapeli.com/dash">Dash</a> every day, multiple times a day, so it was only natural to have a dash snippet that I can use</p>

<p>Dash snippets are basically a way to paste some code using a shortcode, so typing <code>mongoexport</code> in the console pops up a window where I can complete the rest of the command easily without remembering the options.</p>

<p>Here's the Dash snippets</p>

<p><code>
mongoexport --host __host__ --port __port__ --db __db-name__ -u __username__ -p __pass__ --collection __collection__ -q '__query__' --out __filename__.json
</code></p>

<p>And this is what the window looks like when I type the shortcode, I tab through the place holders and there's a no-brainer way to remember the command and the options.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.evernote.com/shard/s54/sh/12b3d1f2-1db6-4263-9776-0b6e209f9be6/d8a1a1191a075b3d2c71262b70e2b86b/res/8d37de67-11a7-4708-a79a-e59b7a278bef/skitch.png?resizeSmall&amp;width=832" alt="dash snippet window" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DO NOT use the callbacks that require persistence in Mongoid]]></title>
    <link href="http://avi.io/blog/2013/02/19/do-not-use-the-callbacks-that-require-persistence-in-mongoid/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-19T22:10:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://avi.io/blog/2013/02/19/do-not-use-the-callbacks-that-require-persistence-in-mongoid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started using MongoDB at <a href="http://www.gogobot.com">Gogobot</a> a little while ago.
While using it, I encountered some <a href="http://avi.io/blog/2013/01/30/problems-with-mongoid-and-sidekiq-brainstorming/">problems</a>, but for the most part, things went pretty smooth.</p>

<p>Today, I encountered a bug that surprised me.</p>

<p>While it certainly should not have, I think it can surprise you as well, so I am writing it up here as a fair warning.</p>

<p>For Gogobot, the entire graph is built on top of MongoDB, all the things social are driven by it and for the most parts like I mentioned, we are pretty happy with it.</p>

<h2>SO, What was the problem?</h2>

<p>The entire graph is a mountable engine, we can decide to turn it on or to turn it off at will.
It acts as a data warehouse and the workflows are being managed by the app.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<p>When model X is created, app is notified and decides what to do with this notification, and so on and so forth.</p>

<p>Everything peachy so far, nothing we haven't used hundreds of times in the past.</p>

<p>Here's how it works.</p>

<p>We have a model called <code>VisitedPlace</code>, it's a representation of a user that visited a certain place</p>

<p>Here's the code</p>

<p>```ruby</p>

<pre><code>module GraphEngine
  class FbPlace
    include Mongoid::Document
    include Mongoid::Timestamps
    include GraphEngine::Notifications::NotifiableModel

    #… rest of code here
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>As you can see, this model includes a module called <code>NotifiableModel</code>, here's the important part from it:</p>

<p>```ruby</p>

<pre><code>module GraphEngine
  module Notifications
    module NotifiableModel
      extend ActiveSupport::Concern

      included do
        after_create do
          send_notification("created")
        end
      end

      def send_notification(verb)
        # Notify the app here...
      end
    end
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>Like I said, pretty standard stuff, nothing too fancy, but here's where it's getting tricky.</p>

<p>This model has a unique index on <code>user_id</code> and <code>place_id</code>. It's a unique index and no two documents can exist in the same collection.</p>

<p>BUT… check this out:</p>

<p><code>ruby
  GraphEngine::VisitedPlace.create!(user_id: 1, place_id: 1) =&gt; true
  GraphEngine::VisitedPlace.create!(user_id: 1, place_id: 1) =&gt; true
</code></p>

<p>The second query actually failed in the DB level, but the application still returned true.</p>

<p>Meaning, that <code>after_create</code> is actually being called even if the record is <strong>not really persisted</strong>.</p>

<h2>How you can fix? / should you fix?</h2>

<p>For Gogobot, I fixed it using safe mode on those models, I don't mind the performance penalty, since I don't want to trigger Sidekiq workers that will do all sorts of things twice or three times.</p>

<p>Should you do the same? I am not sure, you need to benchmark your app and see if you can fix it in another way.</p>

<p>Would love to hear back from you in comments/discussion</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Problems with Mongoid and Sidekiq- Brainstorming]]></title>
    <link href="http://avi.io/blog/2013/01/30/problems-with-mongoid-and-sidekiq-brainstorming/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-30T20:13:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://avi.io/blog/2013/01/30/problems-with-mongoid-and-sidekiq-brainstorming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks back, we started slowly upgrading all of our queues at <a href="http://www.gogobot.com">Gogobot</a> to work with <a href="https://github.com/mperham/sidekiq">Sidekiq</a>.</p>

<p>Posts on how awesome the experience was and how much better Sidekiq is from <a href="http://github.com/defunkt/sidekiq">Resque</a> coming soon, though with all the good came some bad.</p>

<h2>Summary of the solution</h2>

<p>With Sidekiq, we are processing around <strong>25X more</strong> jobs than what we were doing with Resque, processing around 15,000,000 jobs per day, at paces of over 1K per second at times (at peak we go up well past that)</p>

<p>This is how many jobs we processed today…</p>

<p><img src="http://d.pr/i/O9aU+" alt="Sidekiq history graph for today" /></p>

<p>And this is a snapshot of our realtime graph</p>

<p><img src="http://d.pr/i/7Fkr+" alt="Realtime graph snapshot" /></p>

<p>On the MongoDB side we are working with Mongoid and we have a shared environment, 9 shards with 3 replicas in each shard, all running through 2 routers.</p>

<p>Our production mongoid config looks like this</p>

<p>```yaml
production:
  op_timeout: 3
  connection_timeout: 3
  sessions:</p>

<pre><code>default:
  hosts:
    - HOST_NAME:27017 #Single router R0
  username: USER_NAME
  password: PASSWORD
  database: DATABASE_NAME
  options:
    consistency: :eventual
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>We are using latest versions of all relevant gems (Sidekiq, Mongoid, Moped, Redis)</p>

<h2>All seems fine right? What's the problem?</h2>

<p>The problem is that we have too many connections opening and closing to our mongo instances. (~25-40 new connections per second).</p>

<p>Each time a job is picked up, a connection to Mongo is opened and when the job is done, this connection is closed (using Kiqstand middleware).</p>

<p>This is causing huge loads on our router server, and causing mongo to run out of file descriptors at times.</p>

<h2>SO?</h2>

<p>More then anything, this post is a callout for discussion with anyone using similar solution with similar scale and can assist, I know I would love to brainstorm on how to solve this problem.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
