<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: BuyersVote.com | Brian Armstrong]]></title>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/categories/buyersvote-com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-11T14:36:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Armstrong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Worst Idea Ever, Or Absolutely Brilliant (You Decide)]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/worst-idea-ever-or-absolutely-brilliant-you-decide/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-02T23:09:07-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/worst-idea-ever-or-absolutely-brilliant-you-decide</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was watching <a href="https://www.openforum.com/idea-hub/topics/marketing/video/made-to-stick-how-to-stand-out-in-a-crowded-marketplace?">this video</a> today about how to stand out in your market place.  It gives some good examples of companies (like VooDoo Donut and ZipCar) who created a strong following by:</p>

<ol>
<li>Doing something different</li>
<li>Having fun</li>
<li>Not being afraid to be a little weird</li>
</ol>


<p>It reminded me of Google's "I'm feeling lucky" button or Facebook's <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/09/19/once-again-facebook-owns-talk-like-a-pirate-day-on-the-web/">Pirate</a> language setting.</p>

<p>It also reminded me of some of the ideas I wrote about in <a href="http://brianarmstrong.org/posts/how-to-generate-word-of-mouth-for-your-business/">word of mouth marketing</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Then I started looking at the </strong><a href="http://BuyersVote.com"><strong>BuyersVote.com</strong></a><strong> homepage and I got sort of sad.  It looked really boring.</strong></p>

<p>It looked like every other review site out there.  If I saw it for the first time, I'd probably be sort of confused, do a few clicks, and then leave.</p>

<p>So I started wondering, what is this website actually ABOUT damnit.  It's got to convey it instantly.  And I blurted out "it just so you can find out if something sucks or not before you buy it!"</p>

<p>So I decided to change the tag-line of the site from "Online product reviews made easy" to "Find out if it sucks, before you buy!"</p>

<p>Irreverent?  Yes.  Junevile?  Probably.  Fun and engaging?  I think so.  At least it would cause me to give it a second look, and maybe even participate in this community - it's sounds fun.</p>

<p>What do you think?  Worst idea ever or good marketing?  I think I'll test it out for a bit.</p>

<p><a href="http://buyersvote.com"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/buyersvote1.png" alt="BuyersVote.com" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://buyersvote.com"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/12/buyersvote-logo.png" alt="BuyersVote.com New Tagline" /></a></p>

<p><strong>P.S. Because it worked out so well </strong><a href="http://brianarmstrong.org/posts/300-increase-in-traffic-to-buyersvote-com-last-month/"><strong>last time</strong></a><strong>, I've started a new category on BuyersVote for "</strong><a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-christmas-gift-ideas-2009-reviews"><strong>Best Christmas Gift Ideas 2009</strong></a><strong>".  Hopefully you'll find it useful as you do your last minute Christmas shopping.  Please take a moment to go </strong><a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-christmas-gift-ideas-2009-reviews"><strong>check it out now</strong></a><strong> - and don't forget to vote or add your own idea if you have a good one.  Thanks!</strong></p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[300% Increase In Traffic To BuyersVote.com Last Month]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/300-increase-in-traffic-to-buyersvote-com-last-month/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-04T00:41:46-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/300-increase-in-traffic-to-buyersvote-com-last-month</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just wanted to give an update on how my SEO experiment went from <a href="http://brianarmstrong.org/posts/the-best-books-for-entrepreneurs/">this post a month ago</a>.</p>

<p>For those who didn't read it I setup a category on <a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-halloween-costume-ideas-2009-reviews">BuyersVote.com</a> for the best halloween costume ideas of 2009.  I did this because I knew it would be a popular keyword in October, especially toward the end of the month.  And if I could make a good page targeted specifically for that niche keyword, it might get some traffic.</p>

<p>Well, it worked.  I just BARELY got on the first page of Google in time for Halloween and managed to get the 9th or 10th place listing (which is still on the first page) for some costume related keywords.  It was enough to triple the traffic to BuyersVote.com for a month (which isn't saying much given how little it was before, but still, you have to start somewhere ;).</p>

<p>Here is the graph from Google Analytics.</p>

<p><a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/11/Picture-6.png"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/11/Picture-6.png" alt="SEO Halloween Costumes" /></a></p>

<p>Check out the keywords which drove all the traffic.</p>

<p>It's also interesting to note that I think my <a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-halloween-costume-ideas-2009-reviews">page</a> actually had the best content of any of the top 10 listings.  Most of the other pages were made-for-adsense sites or crappy articles without many good costume ideas.  It shows you that crowd-sourced content works, even on a small scale.</p>

<p>So what did I learn from this experiment?  Primarily it shows this could be a good growth strategy for BuyersVote.  With just a few good niche review topics like <a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/u-s-ski-resorts-reviews">Ski Resort Reviews</a>, <a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/blogs-for-entrepreneurs-reviews">Blogs for Entrepreneurs</a>, or <a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/web-browsers-for-mac-reviews">Mac Web Browser Reviews</a> it could start to get some good organic search results.  If I get just a few, that will be enough to start getting new contributors to the site who will generate new topics, and new search results, and it will be come a positive feedback loop to growth.</p>

<p>This is the hardest part about starting a site like this: critical mass.  Nobody wants to be the first reviewer on an empty site.</p>

<p>Feel free to steal this SEO idea too (I didn't come up with it) and apply it to your own site.  Basically just pick a highly specialized keyword (so it's not too competitive) that will have a lot of traffic coming up.  Seasonal or holiday related keywords work well for this.  Then if you generate a page targeted to just that keyword, it's possible to get on the first page of Google, even if you have a relatively new or unknown site.</p>

<p><strong>What do you think?  What might be some other good niche topics to add to BuyersVote.com?</strong></p>

<p>By the way, the site now has 405 items and 113 contributors, so if you haven't already, please take a moment to <a href="http://buyersvote.com/user_session/new">create an account</a> and add some reviews.</p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Books For Entrepreneurs]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/the-best-books-for-entrepreneurs/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-04T15:02:59-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/the-best-books-for-entrepreneurs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes I post up <a href="http://brianarmstrong.org/posts/how-to-generate-word-of-mouth-for-your-business/">reviews</a> of books I've enjoyed.</p>

<p>But I think it'd be interesting to get a collective approach from all the readers of this blog.  What books on business have had the greatest impact on you?  Which book do you find yourself recommending to other entrepreneurs the most?</p>

<p>A bunch of suggestions have already been added to BuyersVote.com.  What would you add or subtract?  You can <a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-books-for-entrepreneurs-reviews">check out the list here</a> to add your two cents.</p>

<p><a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-books-for-entrepreneurs-reviews"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/10/Picture-2.png" alt="Picture 2" /></a></p>

<p>In case you've never used BuyersVote.com before, here is a quick review of how it works (it's really simple):</p>

<ul>
<li><p>If you like an item, vote it up (+1)</p></li>
<li><p>If you don't like an item, vote it down (-1)</p></li>
<li><p>If you have a better idea, add it at the bottom</p></li>
</ul>


<p>You'll have to <a href="http://buyersvote.com/user_session/new">login</a> to vote (sorry, that is the only way I could find to keep voting fair), but you can use your Google account or one you already have so there is no registration process.</p>

<p>This isn't really related, but another category that I put together recently on BuyersVote is for the <a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-halloween-costume-ideas-2009-reviews">best halloween costume ideas of 2009</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://buyersvote.com/categories/best-halloween-costume-ideas-2009-reviews"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/10/Picture-12.png" alt="Best Halloween Costume Ideas 2009" /></a></p>

<p>As you can see, some of them are good, some are bad (maybe even offensive).  But this is the beauty of crowd sourced data.  Good ideas get pushed to the top and bad ideas get pushed down (with enough participants).</p>

<p>I actually have an ulterior motive for this category: I'm hoping to get on the first page of Google for keywords related to Halloween costume ideas this season!  There will obviously be quite a bit of traffic over the next month for those keywords and, if it works, some new people will be introduced to BuyersVote that wouldn't have otherwise seen it.  This is a nice little marketing technique that you might want to try: target a highly specific seasonal keyword.  If you can get on the first page of Google for it, you might be able to ride a nice wave of traffic that few other people are competing for.</p>

<p>Until next time, keep breaking free!
Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BIG ANNOUNCEMENT: BuyersVote.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/big-announcement-buyersvotecom/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-22T02:51:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://brianarmstrong.org/blog/big-announcement-buyersvotecom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The announcement is finally here! In the last week I launched <a href="http://buyersvote.com">BuyersVote.com</a>.</p>

<p>Here is the description from the <a href="http://buyersvote.com/about">about</a> page which describes the site:<a href="http://buyersvote.com"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://buyersvote.com"><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/oldbloguploads/2009/04/picture-11.png" alt="BuyersVote.com" /></a></p>

<p>=====================================</p>

<h3>Friends help you make buying decisions every day...</h3>

<blockquote><p>This phone is great!</p>

<p>That mechanic is a crook!</p></blockquote>

<p>We know we can trust our friends (unlike advertisements) because they aren't selling us anything.</p>

<p>Wouldn't it be great if you could ask a friend about EVERY product you wanted to buy before you bought it?</p>

<p>Wouldn't it be even better if dozens or hundreds of people could tell you about their experience with it and any related products too? One person might be biased or get it wrong but surely if you could AVERAGE the reviews of hundreds of people you could know which was best.</p>

<h3>The power is now in YOUR hands (the consumer)...</h3>

<p>The internet has enabled consumers from all around the world to COLLABORATE - sharing their collective experiences to let each other know what is good and what is bad.</p>

<p>Online reviews are nothing new of course. You can find a great book on Amazon, a great hotel on TripAdvisor, and a great digital camera on CNet - all from reading opinions of real people who have already used the product.</p>

<p>But what about the myriad of other products that DON'T have a dedicated, trusted, portal on the web?</p>

<p>If you aren't searching for a major consumer good on a website you already trust, you'll often get back junk pages full of affiliate links, biased reviews by one person, or endless forum posts that you don't have time to read and summarize.</p>

<blockquote><p>What if there was a site that was <strong>community editable</strong> - just like Wikipedia - so that ANYBODY and EVERYBODY could create reviews for any product they wanted?</p></blockquote>

<p>And what if it was completely free?</p>

<p>What I have just described of course is BuyersVote.com - a community editable site where anybody can create and edit pages for any product, service, or company in the world.</p>

<p>A trusted, portal site can now be formed for <strong>niche products</strong>, <strong>mainstream products</strong>, <strong>local products</strong>, <strong>individual service providers</strong> and anything else that people or companies want to rate and review.</p>

<p>Imagine...</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Choosing a bank, credit card, or cell phone company based on thousands of votes from their real customers</p></li>
<li><p>Doctors and hospitals making more informed purchases of medical equipment</p></li>
<li><p>Accountants collaborating to choose the right software</p></li>
<li><p>Finding the right lawyer, wedding planner, plumber, or realtor in your neighborhood based on reviews from actual customers</p></li>
<li><p>Companies being able to choose the right vendors and suppliers based on past performance</p></li>
<li><p>Mothers rating private schools</p></li>
<li><p>Motorcycle riders rating biker bars</p></li>
<li><p>Exotic pet lovers describing their favorite species of tarantula</p></li>
</ul>


<p>The sky is really the limit here.</p>

<blockquote><p>People and businesses have millions of different interests, needs, and areas of expertise. Now they have a place to read and create trusted reviews on ANY topic they'd like.</p></blockquote>

<p>They could even end up creating a way to rate things which aren't products (charities, blogs, speakers at a conference, etc). That is part of the beauty - BuyersVote so open ended that I have no idea WHAT people will do with it and that is great.</p>

<p>YOU are in control on this site, YOU are the editor, and YOU can create whatever you'd like.</p>

<h3>Quality Control And Reputation</h3>

<p>We've also taken things one step further than Wikipedia by building a reputation system - a quality control if you will - right into BuyersVote.</p>

<blockquote><p>When you make an edit or post a review on BuyersVote, other users will be able mark your contributions as helpful or not. Over time, you will build a reputation on BuyersVote (the little number by your username) which is an indication of how much the community trusts you.</p></blockquote>

<p>This is great for a few reasons. First, it means that the community is "self-policing". If a malicious user tries to deface a page or insert their opinion where facts should go (a major problem on Wikipedia), the community will vote them down and their editing privileges will be removed.</p>

<p>Second, it means that well trusted contributors will gain new privileges and will essentially be full administrators of BuyersVote. They will be able to delete pages, flag them, re-categorize them, combine them, etc.</p>

<h3>Consumer Reports, Wikipedia, and the Better Business Bureau In One</h3>

<p>One of the most exciting parts about this website for me personally is the idea that it can not only help good companies rise to the top and be rewarded - but also that it will ensure bad companies get punished and won't be able to keep taking advantage of new consumers.</p>

<p>Almost everyone has had a BAD experience at some point in their life with a product or service. Maybe it was a piece of junk and they refused to honor the warranty. Maybe it was an individual or company who took your money and never delivered the result.</p>

<p>Taking them to court can be a hassle, so you might be stuck - only able to warn your friends about it and share your story. The company might lose one or two new customers (depending on how many friends you have) but chances are they wouldn't feel the effect and would go right on doing the same thing to other people.</p>

<p>But what if you had several MILLION "friends" who could now read about your experience online? What if when people typed the company's name into Google your review came up at the top? I bet that shady company might start to listen.</p>

<blockquote><p>The next time a company or individual treats your poorly, do the world a favor and make a PUBLIC RECORD of your experience on BuyersVote.com. Let the world know how you were treated and you might just save someone else the same fate!</p></blockquote>

<p>If we all work together we can actually eliminate unethical companies by making this information freely available. Bad companies will either have to clean up their act or go out of business once it's public knowledge how bad they really are.</p>

<p>In fact, I suggest that when creating a page on BuyersVote you use the individual or company's REAL NAME. If their name is John Smith and they are a realtor, make a page for them called "John Smith (Realtor)". If they are a company, write their actual company name.</p>

<p>Why? Because when someone does a Google search for this person or company's name, you want your review to come up first telling the world to beware.</p>

<h3>Final Thoughts...</h3>

<p>By no means should BuyersVote ONLY be a negative place for bad reviews. It should also be a place to highlight the BEST in any field and help people make the right buying decisions.</p>

<p>The vast majority of people and companies in the world are good and I hope the site will reflect that. Overall I'm very excited for what BuyersVote.com will become.</p>

<p>Remember that...</p>

<ul>
<li><p>BuyersVote is a "wiki" just like Wikipedia - meaning that anyone can create or edit a page on this site</p></li>
<li><p>Anyone can write a review on this site</p></li>
<li><p>BuyersVote is 100% FREE</p></li>
<li><p>The next time you need some information on what to buy, do a search for it here first</p></li>
<li><p>If you have a specific interest or experience (good or bad) with a certain product, service, or company - create a page for it</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Thank you so much, and I'll see you around BuyersVote!
Brian Armstrong</p>

<p>=====================================</p>

<p>I'll be describing more about the site over the next few weeks on this blog such as:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>How I developed it quickly using Ruby on Rails and plugins</p></li>
<li><p>How I got the web hosting for free</p></li>
<li><p>The design</p></li>
<li><p>The philosophy behind easy logins</p></li>
<li><p>And more...</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>But for right now please do me a favor and <a href="http://buyersvote.com">click here to view the site</a>.</strong></p>

<p><strong>Then please try <a href="http://buyersvote.com/pages/new">adding a page to the site</a>. It can be on any product or service you have used recently, perhaps an area you have a particular interest or specialized knowledge in, or someone you've had a particularly good/bad experience with.</strong></p>

<p><strong>There is no login required to add a page, but if you want to login you can do so <a href="http://buyersvote.com/user_session/new">with an existing account</a> you already have (Google, Yahoo, Facebook, Aol, etc).</strong></p>

<p>Please post feedback in the comments below on...</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Your first impression (whether bad or good)</p></li>
<li><p>What is confusing or unclear about it</p></li>
<li><p>What you like, what you dislike</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Thank you so much!</p>

<p>Brian Armstrong</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
